HELLO AND WELCOME TO JAVA design patterns.
My name is Jason Fenn and I'll be your instructor.
First off I want to thank you for signing up for the class.
It's gonna be a ton of fun and I'm going to do my best to motivate you and help you learn all about
design patterns using Java.
I'm really excited let's get started.
I wanted to start off to tell you just a little bit about my background so you can understand what my
knowledge base is.
My educational background is I have a Master's of Science and Computer Science from Binghamton University.
It's a school in upstate New York.
I graduated in around 2000.
I've been a software developer for over 16 years and the workforce and I've been an online instructor
for over 11 years.
So I have a vast amount of experience.
I've instructed over 20 different classes.
This is everything from object oriented programming to compiler theory.
I've taught many many different classes and I have a lot of experience in computer programming.
I've been working with the Java programming language for over 20 years.
Our first class in college and about nineteen ninety four was in Java and so the first language that
I used in a lot of practice was the Java programming language.
I think I learned basic first but Java was really that first language that I got comfortable with and
I've been utilizing design patterns throughout my entire career because those are the best programming
practices.
And you write a lot of high quality code by following design patterns and why that's one of the reasons
why this class is so important.
I've created beginner Java and I've created design pattern courses at multiple universities.
Currently I'm a software developer Xerox Corp. basically writes a software for multi functional printing
devices mainly using the C programming language and also using Java for our front end graphical user
interfaces.
But no matter what if it's C or Java I'm always using design patterns again to write high quality code.
I mainly concentrated my career on object oriented languages and mobile programming.
That's where the excitement is.
That's where a lot of what I enjoy doing.
That's what's fun for me.
But as always whenever I write my code I try to focus on writing high quality code.
A lot of times there's not a important distinction placed on high quality code.
And so I try to emphasize that in all my courses.
It's not good enough to just produce the correct output.
You want to make sure that your code is very easy to maintain properly cohesive and loosely coupled.
So that's what we're going to focus on.
Let's talk a little bit about the class and some of the topics that we're going gonna cover.
We'll start off by giving an overview of design patterns.
I'll give you a definition.
I'll describe a little history.
I like to do this because because it provides some context it will give you information on when did
this concept start and why is it important.
We'll talk about some of the advantages of design patterns.
Why do you use design patterns and when you when you write code what are the benefits of it.
Why even do this method.
So I'll focus on all those advantages mainly to write highly reusable software to make your code easier
to maintain.
To make it loosely coupled highly cohesive you're going to see that here these common themes throughout
the course will dive right in and talk about the different types of design patterns mainly talk about
how design patterns are categorized how they're there three separate topics really creation will behavior
structural and each one of those topics identify a subset of patterns that you can use to solve specific
problems so criminal patterns have to do with creating instances of objects behavior patterns have to
do with patterns in objects communicate and then structural patterns we'll talk about the structure
of objects.
After concluding with the overview and giving this the nice introduction we're going to dive right into
really important design principles and strategies.
These are related to me mainly all languages but we're going to focus on Java.
This is an important section because it relates to the design patterns concepts so all the design parents
that you learn and learn in this class are going to employ these principles and strategies.
So that's why we talk about the principles of strategies first because you need to be able to relate
the patterns that you learn to these concepts and so forth.
We're talk about design smells.
This is a common term.
You learn about in programming that has to do with mainly things that you see in the code that tells
you something is wrong with the design that's referred to as a smell.
It's like almost something like you see some bad behavior in your design.
So we first want to point out what are some things that you can see in your code that tells you that
you're not utilizing good concepts because again good concepts is everything that you want to follow
when you write design patterns and then really the other related strategies are all related all again
characteristics of design patterns.
So programming to an interface.
This is an important thing and we'll go into this in detail composition over inheritance when you utilize
a has a relationship versus is a relationship.
We'll talk about delegation principles where to put responsibility in different objects.
We'll dive right in the Single Responsibility Principle which is mainly about cohesion.
This concept of objects should do small focused things.
They shouldn't be all over the place.
They shouldn't be doing 10 different things.
We'll talk about the open closed principle where objects are open for extension of a closed for modification.
And again this helps with the maintenance phase of the software lifecycle.
It reduces your bugs it's easier to find bugs and it also makes the code much more extensible you can
you can add new code.
We'll talk about the list coughs substitution principle.
We'll talk about interface segregation principle and that will wind up ending our design patterns.
We will then conclude our design principle the strategy section by talking about dependency mainly inversion
and injection the differences between because again all these concepts are important.
If you learn design patterns you have to understand these principles.
After we learn about all the principles we'll dive into a couple prerequisites for the course in terms
of design.
We'll talk about UML Unified modeling language.
This is mainly a documentation tool that can describe designed to you so design patterns are all about
following good programming practice reusable software and in order to understand how these patterns
work.
You have to understand how to design and so we're going to show you class diagrams.
I'm going to show you maybe some other object type diagrams sequence diagrams you need to understand
these diagrams and what they document in order to understand the design pattern.
So we'll just do a quick rundown of UML.
Talk about class diagrams and an object oriented references mainly things related to inheritance interfaces
composition and annotation simple drawing symbols and the documentation tools.
Then we're gonna divide the course basically into those three sections.
We're gonna discuss all 22 patterns that the Gang of Four came up with in nineteen ninety four around.
So we'll start off with the creation of design patterns.
As I mentioned this has to do with creating instances of objects.
We'll run through about five patterns factory Abstract Factory.
Those are related and then the Singleton singletons of real popular one that we'll discuss it allows
you to create a single instance of an object.
This is important when you want to create programs that only have one instance so maybe a program that
simulates a printer or different hardware.
We'll dive into the builder and the prototype and we'll go into all the details of these patterns in
each one of these sections.
We'll follow that up by talking about the structural design patterns.
And there is basically 7 structural design patterns that will discuss listed right here adaptor Napster's
and other real popular one.
The last two incompatible objects to be able to talk to one another bridge composite decorator which
decorator can be an alternative sub classing the facade the fly away in the proxy will end all of our
discussion on design patterns by talking about the behavior design patterns how objects communicate
with one another we'll talk about chain of responsibility command interpreter Iterator iterator you
probably have a somewhat fundamental understanding of through the Java collection classes how you can
go through different elements in a data structure we'll talk about the mediator the momento observer's
of real popular one it's a good way that you can communicate with many different objects follow that
up with the state strategy template method and then we'll end the course with the visitor design pattern
we'll have a couple more lectures after discussing design patterns they have to deal with basically
maybe some future sub topics that you can be more specific to Java patterns maybe related to the spring
framework we'll talk a little bit about even bigger or larger patterns related to architecture like
MVC in the model view controller but that will be touched upon Well we really want to focus on the class
is the twenty two design patterns related to the Gang of Four and related to the Java programming language
why we're doing all these introduction and lectures we're going to have all sorts of different challenges
and challenges are really just assignments I want to try to make it is fun and exciting for you to learn
about design patterns by providing these challenges solutions I don't want to just go through demonstrations
or provide power points I want to make this fun for you.
So we're gonna have some assignments we'll have solutions to those assignments we're going to have a
ton of coding examples I'll be using the IDC we'll go through specifically we'll be using intelligence
so we'll go through many examples intelligent.
Most of you or hopefully all of you have been proficient in intelligence it's really the main idea you
want to use for Java development but it's gonna be a lot of fun.
I mean all these job examples will help you become a better job programmer but also help you write nice
high quality code.
The course is really organized around this theory.
We're going to talk about design patterns I want to tell you why they're important and I'm going to
provide examples and then addition to understanding all of the why in the theory behind it I'm not going
to provide a more practical solution by providing a ton of demonstrations in the idea itself writing
the code.
So I'm hoping it'll be very well rounded.
A lot of you know a lot of instructors Sarah you dummy they focus just on the code right.
They don't necessarily tell you a lot of the the why behind it.
They just say hey this is how you do something.
This is how you do it and that's great and everything but it's not always important to just know how
you have to know what you're doing right.
You have to understand the concepts behind it.
The theory behind what you're doing and why it's a good way to do this.
So we're gonna go with a two pronged approach by both discussing theory in detail and many many many
demonstrations to get you have practical examples so that you can become proficient in actually writing
and using design patterns.
We'll be doing a ton of hands on coding as I mentioned tons of demonstrations using intelligence and
writing tons of Java code.
The outcomes of the course at the end of the course.
This is basically what you want to have learned.
I want you to understand the fundamentals of design patterns right.
Why do we use the design patterns.
What are the advantages of them.
Why are they good programming practice.
How does it help you become a better job programmer.
I want you to be able to create job applications using the design patterns that are discussed in class.
I don't want to just tell you what design patterns are.
And then after the after the course you just kind of forget about it.
I want you to be able to actually say all the adapter.
I know what that is.
I can write a job application that that uses the adapter that's going to be very important.
I want you to be able to master the art of problem solving in problem programming using efficient proven
methods.
So we all know that programming is all about problem solving.
You become a better problem solver when you understand the right approaches to solve the problems.
If you're continually solving problems and you're using the wrong approach you're never gonna get better.
So we want to follow these proven methods.
We want to follow these design patterns that utilize good high quality design strategies so that when
you write the code you're actually following these design principles right.
You're you're making the code easier to maintain.
Easier to debug and just easier to add new features.
I mean that's really what it's all about.
You don't want to just write code and just get the output to work.
You know I always tell all my students getting the output correct is only one phase of writing the code.
You have to focus on high quality software using good design principles mainly because the maintenance
phase of the software lifecycle is so important and so expensive delivering the code is only one phase
maintaining for the next 15 years for people to use it is really the most important thing.
So we're going to focus on all these nice things and that is really just having to write high quality
Java code.
All right we're going to be using Java eleven latest version and we're going focus on module code that
objects that are highly cohesive you have good encapsulation and low coupling.
We don't want a lot of dependencies between these objects because the more dependencies the harder it
is to debug.
So throughout the course as we as we present these design pattern concepts we're going to focus on high
quality.
You're going to become proficient in basic design principles right.
So in addition to these design patterns because the design patterns follow all these principles you're
not going to have the added benefit of understanding the risk of substitution principle of understanding
as single responsibility principle.
These are all standard design strategies that all high quality programmers know.
So you're going to have that added benefit.
And lastly you're going to have fun right.
I don't want this to be a boring class.
I want you to fall asleep during lectures or demonstrations.
I want to enjoy what you're doing because otherwise it doesn't always stick up in your brain right.
If you do if you're not having fun if it's boring monotonous and you don't actually know what you're
doing it's very hard to learn.
So I want to try to make this a fun class where you learn a lot of important formation about design
mainly design patterns but also design principles so I'm looking forward to this.
It's gonna be a lot of fun.
And again I thank you for signing up for the course.
Let's get started.
Thank you.