Hello and welcome back.
In this lecture I wanted to talk a little bit about how the class is organized.
The reason I wanted to provide this quick short lecture is so that it can help you better decide on
whether or not you want to sign up for the class purchase the class.
So this class is a little different than many of the classes on you dummy and that it's not just a how
to.
This class is organized around explaining all the concepts of programming language.
It's really focused on the why in addition to providing the how I'm going to provide many how tos on
how to write certain programs and demonstrate different concepts.
But again it's a little unique in that it's just not a how to you're going to understand concepts you're
going to understand why you're doing the things you're doing when you're writing your code.
So it's a complete learning experience at the end of this class you're going to fully understand the
program language specifically you're going to understand how the programming language works and all
the concepts associated with that language.
And again as I mentioned earlier I find this is lacking in many of the Udemy courses.
Many of the NUMMI courses are nothing more than demonstrations of projects of of certain how tos on
how to create a particular coding project without fully understanding what you're doing or why you're
doing it.
I also want to describe how I'm going to present this information and how you're going to learn it.
First and foremost we're going to have all video lectures you know that policy and you dummy is mainly
that the way they can provide a lot of some of the exact some of the material is going to provide it
through PowerPoint slides and some people are negative on PowerPoint slides.
They don't really like to learn from PowerPoint slides.
They're just real not keen on it.
The reason I provide PowerPoint slides is because I have to provide these concepts and definitions often
is the case and they're very abstract and I can't just go into an idea and demonstrate the code.
I have to provide the content some kind of text.
Now I could provide that notepad word pad.
Any other editor I choose PowerPoint slide PowerPoint because it has a nice visual representation and
it's very useful in that manner.
I'm not going to just be reading from the slides so I will hear some complaints often in other classes
where hey you're using PowerPoint slides and you just going to read from them.
Well no I'm not just going to read from them.
I'm going to provide insight via my experience.
So the PowerPoint slides again they're designed to provide for you the understanding of the material.
I'm not sure any other way I can do that without providing at least some PowerPoint slides especially
concerning abstract concepts and definitions.
I just don't know no other way to do it.
You have to listen and you have to try to understand from it.
Now that doesn't mean we're going to not going to provide other concepts of learning but there are going
to be PowerPoint slides so I understand that coming in the class.
And these are going to contain thorough explanations VMI experience.
It's a way for you to understand the concepts in the class.
It's not the only thing that I'm to provide but you are going to see a PowerPoint slide.
So don't just necessarily get negative on the entire class because there are PowerPoint slides.
It's one technique in helping you learn.
And I think a technique that needs that is needed in the class in addition to the PowerPoint slides.
I'm going to do tons of practical hands on demonstrations of code.
So I'm going to bring up the idea I'm going to bring up an editor I'm going to show you how to write
the code in an editor.
I'm write code examples I'm going to type in the code.
These are gonna be concrete.
They're gonna be real world so if this this type of learning will be more practical and we'll be more
hands on learning.
And I know many students like this and it's needed.
I love it because it's more practical and actually see you can see how I'm writing code.
Again though if I'm if I'm trying to present information or concepts such as polymorphism I also want
to provide a lecture or a PowerPoint slide associate with that to give you a formal definition so that
we don't just dive into the code and then you have to kind of scratch your head and say what exactly
is he doing in the code.
So pi point slides in addition and demonstrations are gonna be provided in this class.
This will help supplement your learning of the language itself.
In addition you need a way to assess how well you're doing in the class in what you're learning and
if you're learning so we're going to provide challenges challenges that are essentially coding assignments
through additional projects how it will work is provide you with this assignment.
I'll tell you the requirements explain maybe give you some tips on how to complete the challenge and
then you'll go off and do it on your own.
And then I'll provide another video which will be a solution to that lecture so you can see whether
or not you did it correctly.
The solution will be a complete walkthrough or what is called a code along of the solution.
I'll go line by line explaining every line of the solution in an integrated developed environment in
an environment where you write your code I'll run it.
I'll demonstrate how it works.
Everything.
And then addition to going through this video walkthrough I'll also provide all the source code to you
so that you can download it and you can compare the source code to your source code in text but again
I wanted to just provide this quick lecture so that you know how the class is organized in terms of
how you're going to learn and what you're paying for.
And if you see a lot of PowerPoint slides try to give you an idea of why provide them and why I think
they're useful.
Again I want to provide a complete learning environment and I don't think I can do that by just doing
a how to of walking through projects.
So I hope you appreciate this lecture and I hope you understand where I'm coming from and how you're
going to learn in this class.
Thank you.