Hello.
Saw.
I'm excited to get started.
First I want to go through a basic overview of design patterns give some definitions give you a little
history and tell you the four common essential parts of a design pattern.
All right so as far as everyday life in the real world we always talk about the way that we do things
right.
Our hobbies our home life and we recognize when we're doing these hobbies and this.
This everyday work that we have power patterns right.
You repeat things.
All right.
When you go to work you get up in the morning you brush your teeth you drive a certain distance certain
place you're doing a lot of repetition and this is the same when it comes to software.
When you write code you end up repeating yourself quite a bit.
So when you repeat yourself these are patterns and if you're going to repeat yourself you can identify
a really good common solution to these patterns.
So software engineers face common problems during development of various software programs and you should
know this as you're writing code.
A lot of times you encounter the same problems.
And so for example when we tell a colleague how we accomplish a tricky bit of programming so that the
colleague doesn't have to recreate it from scratch.
Right.
We help one another out.
You don't want to reinvent the wheel.
You want to be able to say hey I solve this problem.
It was really really tough.
And this is how I solved it.
And when you solve it you want to make sure that your solution was actually tried and tested useful
and it was a good way of solving right.
You don't want to give out patterns of repetition for bad ways to do things.
So when we face these common problems for these common software problems we want to be able to communicate
to other developers how we solve these problems using good techniques and good programming.
So in the past when we found solutions to these common problems there was really no way to tell your
co-worker your or your partner or whoever you were coding with.
There were no standards right there in the documentation.
You couldn't just say hey refer to this go solve it the way I did.
So it becomes a significant problem when you don't have this communication especially when new team
members you have new people write code you have new students develop Java they write new programs and
in the past you can actually tell them Hey once you go solve this common problem like this.
So it became a problem when you have new people to not be able to tell them these good things that you
came up with.
Especially I know that when I first started writing code and a lot of people weren't familiar with design
patterns early on.
It was no way to say hey go solve this problem this way.
Go use the adapter go use the factory method that just didn't exist.
And so when you don't have these techniques these documentation these patterns that you can reuse they're
not documented anywhere they're not even thought of.
It takes a lot of effort to become familiar with an existing product it just really it's just gonna
save you time.
If you have somewhere that's documented that you can solve common problems common solutions.
They were something that was created to help solve these common solutions to common problems.
And they're mainly aimed towards object oriented programming languages.
And obviously this is Java class we're going to focus on Java.
But you can use the design patterns that we're going to study and see plus plus C sharp any object oriented
language Smalltalk all the popular ones out there designing object going to software is hard.
Designing reusable object oriented software is even harder.
OK.
So if there's some kind of concept or some pattern that you can study that helps with that it's tremendously
advantage advantageous so design patterns address these issues that I just mentioned.
They help solve common problems in software with provide providing common software solutions in documenting
that so it's a standard that's provided.
It's really really helps give directions to new developers or even experienced developers on how to
solve these common core software problems.
Very very important to learn as it helps you become a much much better programmer and designer.
So I wanted to go through some definitions just some formal definitions to so you can kind of hear other
thoughts of other other important people in the field.
So when you have these different definitions helps you see some different perspective.
So the real probably the real most popular one you've heard is design patterns are reoccurring solutions
to design problems you see over and over and over.
All right pretty straightforward design patterns constitute a set of rules describing how to accomplish
certain tasks in the realm of software development.
Again you're going to notice these these definitions relatively say the same thing common software solutions
common problems design patterns focus more on reuse of recurring and architectural design themes while
frameworks focus on detail design and implementation.
So this definition is kind of distinguishing between frameworks versus specific design patterns design
planners tend to solve smaller subsets of problems.
Framework is much larger and much more detail oriented pattern addresses of reoccurring design problem
that arises in specific design situations and presents a solution to it.
Patterns identify and specify abstractions that are above the level of single classes and instances
or of components so these are just good definitions that again can give you a good summary or good information
on what the goal of Design Patterns are what do they do.
And again it really just comes down to I know I've said this a couple times what really comes down to
common software solutions to common software problems.
So they represent the best practices used by experienced and experienced object oriented programming.
You don't want to reinvent the wheel like I said there's no reason for you to rewrite a solution to
a common problem.
It's been done it's been tried and tested right.
These solutions to general problems have been faced throughout the history of programming.
People come up with great solutions reuse those great solutions.
Right.
So through trial and error through numerous software experienced developers these are tried and tested
software solutions that you should use.
So that's what you're going to study in this class these great solutions that past experience developers
have come up with.
It's going to save your mom a tremendous amount of time as well.
So it's design patterns are not just about the design of objects.
Design is a broad field.
Usually you'll design your software before you actually go and implement and write the code.
If you don't do that you're going to run to a lot of issues.
But what you can think about when think when you you know when you come this concept of design patterns
also think about the interaction between objects.
How do objects communicate.
How do they work together.
So in addition to design high level and low level detail design in some instances there's also strategies
for object inheritance in containment.
You're going to see a law of the same themes repeated over and over while we discuss design patterns
terms like abstraction.
Right.
Inheritance encapsulation you can hear things like coupling cohesion you're going to hear a lot of design
terminology that help you understand these good software solutions design patterns can exist at many
levels from very low level specific solutions to more generalized system issues.
So we'll see all sorts of different solutions that are more broad more general and some more detailed
as far as the history.
Again just to give you some context if you're not if you're not interested in learning about the history
you can skip this but I like to when I when I approach a subject I like to understand all of it the
concept design patterns originated from Christopher Wolfgang Alexander he was from Australia and he
was an architect.
He had nothing to do with software.
He architected buildings.
He learned how to build town different buildings and towns.
He had no computer programming experience running software.
And he came up with this concept after he noticed.
Again a lot of repetition when designing building says an architect.
He said each pattern describes a problem which occurs over and over again in our environment and then
describes the core of the solution to that problem in such a way that you can use the solution a million
times over without ever doing it the same way twice.
That was his definition and he was really the first guy that came up with even the concept of repetition
in nineteen ninety four ninety five.
There was a gang of four gang of four these four architects developers where everyone to calm that took
Alexander's concept and applied it to software software development.
Their names are Eric gamma Richard Howe Ralph Johnson and John plus seats.
Excuse my mispronunciation.
These are the four main guys that came up with the twenty three basic patterns that we're going to discuss
in this course.
And I mentioned I always get it kind of always kind of jump back and forth between 22 and 23 three but
we're going to focus on twenty three sometimes I'll make a mistake and say twenty two but there's twenty
three patterns that we're going to focus upon focus on in this class they were developed and created
by these four four programmers they expressed solutions in terms of objects and interfaces instead of
walls and doors.
All right.
So they took this concept from Alexander and said hey this this the software solutions let's apply this
to objects interfaces inheritance whatever whatever the case may be they saw the advantages of this
of how you have these common solutions cough common software problems.
So what happened was they basically created a book Design Patterns elements of reasonable object or
software that was published nineteen ninety five.
I'll be using this book quite a bit in the class.
A lot of references to it because it's the book that created design patterns and documented all the
useful ones.
So we're going to utilize this book a lot for our learning.
What this book did was it basically applied the idea of patterns to software design and they came up
with the name design patterns because it is just repetition it's just a pattern they describe a structure
within which to catalogue and describe these patterns know they organized when they said hey let's figure
out what these common problems are.
Let's give him a name let's give him certain advantages let's give some implementation details and so
forth.
They catalog these 23 such patterns that we're going to study in this class.
They postulated object oriented strategies and approaches based on the design patterns and that's really
it.
I mean they just came up with some good solutions using good design approaches they did not create the
patterns described in the book.
So I may may have used that term previously but they didn't actually create it right because we know
that these patterns existed in the past.
They just documented right.
They identified the problems that are exist that were common problems.
They said hey you know my colleague always encounters this problem for two incompatible types can't
communicate let's call that the adapter my other I've noticed over 20 years of programming that I always
have a problem where I only want to create one instance of my object.
Let's let's document that and call that Singleton.
So these patterns reflected what had been learned about high quality designs for specific problems.
And again these are high quality.
These are for really smart people that said based on my experience and based on the history in all these
different information.
This is the patterns that we want to focus on these are the most popular ones.
And they basically identified four essential elements to all patterns should have all design patterns
should have a pattern name right.
If you don't have a name.
How you gonna refer to how you can even tell your colleague Hey use this.
So they came up with this idea that patterns have to have names.
They described the problem the solution and the consequences.
In a word or two.
So I provided some examples in our first lecture.
Examples of design pattern names adaptor facade interpreter iterator they all are one or two words that
really concisely kind of describe what the pattern is going to kind of focus on.
This basically this by providing the same.
It lets a designer design at a higher level of abstraction.
You can talk to your friends and you can say hey try using the adapter for her.
Makes it much easier to communicate.
And it makes it easier to think about the design by just the description of that one or two words.
They also said that every design pattern has to solve a problem right.
I mean that's a purpose.
So they have to explicitly document the problem.
Explain and give some context this might describe specific design problems such as how to represent
algorithms as objects.
And again it's an object oriented focus.
So everything's going to be organized around objects.
It might describe a class or different object structures that are symptomatic of an inflexible design.
So it also may when they describe the problem they may tell you why you don't want to do it this way.
It's very valuable to learn things.
Sometimes when you learn the wrong way first and then tell you how to solve it using the right way because
then you can identify why the right way is so good.
So the problem description also will include usually a list of conditions that must be met before it
makes sense to apply the pattern.
They give you a little information Hey.
This is when you should use the pattern again if you don't have a name you don't have the problem description
and you don't actually understand when to use it.
It's not that useful so they try to provide this basic information pattern name and problem they followed
that up with the solution which is obviously very important.
The solution is going to describe the elements that make up the design the relationships responsibility
and collaboration usually including a class diagram through UML because that succinctly helps describe
the solution.
We'll tell you this is an interface.
These are these are subclasses.
This is how all the objects relate together.
They do not and this is very important.
They do not describe a specific implementation right.
Because this would make it much more restrictive.
Right.
You've got to think of a pattern in terms of a template which can be more generic and applied to many
different situations.
If it was very implementation specific it could only be applied maybe to one language patterns are not
designed to work with just Java or just C++ though they're designed to work with any object oriented
languages.
So the implementations that are described in the book and that are essential for for the design patterns
documentation don't provide detailed implementations.
I will provide detailed them computations in this class using Java.
But traditionally when you hear adaptor and when the Gang of Four create a document of these patterns
they didn't provide a detailed implementation.
They just provided that template.
OK.
You should also understand that the consequences of design patterns this usually includes tradeoffs
advantages when of applying the pattern because sometimes it's not always clear cut.
Right.
Sometimes you may apply the pattern and you say Hey well don't forget this could cause another issue.
There's not always perfect implementations.
It's the best implementation.
It's not always perfect.
So the consequences are porn for evaluating design alternatives and for understanding the cost and the
benefits of applying pattern.
This often concerns space memory issues time trade offs things with performance.
It may actually address different language in implementation issues as well.
For example a design pattern may work well in an object oriented language that supports garbage collection
which one that doesn't or may work well in a language that supports multiple inheritance versus one
that doesn't.
This kind of information will be included in the consequences section so it includes impacts on the
systems flexibility extend ability or portability regarding software reuse.
And these are important concepts as well flexibility extensible and portability.
We'll talk about that when we talk about the advantages of design patterns.
That about does it.
I wanted to give you just a basic overview of what design patterns can do you know what they are definition
a little history and common elements that you'll see associated with design patterns.
Thank you.