Hello and welcome back.
In this lecture I'd like to talk about the advantages of design patterns
so why do we use design patterns.
Most commonly stated reasons for studying and utilizing design patterns are because they enable us to
do the following
they have they provide the best solutions for certain problems faced during soft development.
So I mentioned this quite a lot in the last lecture but it's important point to remember common problems
conference of software solutions and what this basically does is it enables software reuse software
reuse is incredibly important.
If we can reuse existing solutions it will save time and time is a big deal when you're writing code
so it makes it easier to reuse successful designs designs and architecture software reuse is one of
the biggest advantages.
That's why we really want to use them.
The solutions have been tried and tested.
They're going to work experienced developers have come up with the solutions so they're going to work
and things that you know and you have confidence in working is a tremendous advantage.
Learning these patterns helps unexperienced developers learn software design in an easy and faster way
now that they're documented and they're out there for studying.
You get the benefit of learning from other people.
You get a head start on problems that you can avoid as a new and new design new developer.
If you know that people encounter these problems and they have solutions form you you don't have to
waste your time trying to figure it out.
So it helps you avoid reinventing the wheel.
A big big advantage you also use design patterns to basically understand object oriented principles
that achieve high quality design.
You do not want to just write code just to get the correct output.
You want to make sure that your code is easily maintainable.
You can achieve that by writing high quality code high quality code is highly dependent on high quality
design.
So this includes keeping classes separated preventing them from having to know too much about one another.
All right this concept of coupling you don't want to have a lot of dependencies between classes.
It'd be really nice if the class is very highly cohesive it does since it has a single focus inside
its own.
You can take it out you can remove it and it doesn't cause all sorts of problems.
So these three concepts that are important in high quality design are encapsulation inheritance polymorphism
in design patterns heavily use these concepts.
It may not be direct inheritance maybe inheritance through interfaces but these are really important
things.
And this is why you want to study design patterns.
You don't reinvent the wheel and you don't have to and it makes you become a very very high quality
programmer and a high quality designer.
You're gonna be one of the best out there coming up with solutions.
Your employer or subsequent employees employers are gonna want to hire you because you know what you're
doing because you're focusing on high quality.
So this is why we use design patterns.
We also use them because it improves communication either amongst your team or just code developers
you're working with on other teams.
You have this common platform right.
We talked about design patents and what they do and how they have a name a description a problem.
You can easily talk to your co-workers and say hey what do you think of the adapter in this in this
particularly situation.
Yeah I think that's a good solution.
So it's good provide.
It provides a good com point of reference during the analysis and design phase of a project.
It allows you to describe your programming approach succinctly in terms that other programs can easily
understand.
You just throw around these words and it really speeds up the process.
So program is conferred a program that uses a single object as a singleton.
Hey hey Mike I need to use a singleton.
Oh he knows exactly what you mean.
Oh Singleton you only need to create one instance.
All right.
I use that before.
That's a great solution.
More on inexperienced junior team members can see that the senior developers who know the design patterns
have something of value it makes them want to learn from you.
Right.
So the junior members will respect you more they'll ask you for help but want to learn from you.
So provides motivation and it really really helps more low or low level or inexperienced programmers
become better programmers by learning these powerful concepts.
It also gives a higher perspective on the problem at a higher level.
Again concerning design and object oriented analysis and design I don't go into analysis it is really
a tough thing to understand you know analyze requirements come up with a really suitable design and
if you can have that high perspective by understanding design patterns it's going to again it because
abstraction is such a big deal when it comes to design patterns.
You don't have to worry about the details too early when you look at a design pattern you understand
them and you're now trying to solve a problem.
You can take a step back so helps a designer get a design that is correct and of high quality much faster
than it was in the past without using design patterns it improves modify ability and maintain ability
of code.
What this means is you can actually change the code much easier without breaking everything you can
find and fix bugs much easier because if you use a design pattern that design pattern is very loosely
coupled and so it's going to it's a very high cohesive code so you're going to be able to find a fix
bugs easier and get coupling and cohesion I've used those terms we'll talk about in more detail but
those are really important terms to understand when you have time tested solutions that have evolved
into structures that can handle change more readily than will often first comes to mind as a solution.
So you have to be able to change things.
Software is constantly evolving.
It's constantly changing and you have all these other team members or other developers modifying that
code.
If it's hard to change something it's gonna be a nightmare.
So making the code easily changeable is going to be a big huge deal and design patterns allow that because
the improved documentation results from the common terminology people.
Again I mentioned this before but it's improved communication.
The code is much easier to understand much easier to maintain because of these great patterns and solutions.
So that's why we use design patterns.
All right.
You know really really important there to understand that if you don't understand why you're using them
why you're studying them shouldn't really be in this course.
It provides high quality solutions improves maintenance.
Much easier to find bugs fixed problems.
What specific problems are addressed by design patterns.
Well they solve many of the day to day problems object oriented designers face in and they solve them
in many different ways.
So how do a data fire the appropriate objects to utilize or create one thing when you first are writing
code and you first first start coming up with some kind of solution or design is an object oriented
language you ask yourself what objects should I include in the system.
And a lot of times you're you're you know you dump on you don't know where to start.
Some classes may tell you OK well describe the system in terms of you know a narrative paragraph and
then identify the nouns the nouns are going to be your objects but really the best way to understand
what objects are appropriate for a given situation is through experience and through learning design
patterns they greatly help identify objects and such because basically they're documented they tell
you exactly what objects you need.
So object packages both data and the procedures that operate on that data it's a problem that you have
to identify and can help with design patterns how to specify object interfaces.
All right.
We all know what an interfaces its contract basically between a client and somebody that wants to use
that and the interface itself interfaces are really really advantageous because they provide this abstraction
and they allow for isolation.
So when you come up with and how to identify an interface that's a problem that you face in design patterns
can help with this every operation declared by an object specifies the operations name the object takes
as parameters and the operations return value.
This makes it very easy to create the interface.
So the interface characterizes the complete set of requests that can be sent to the object
how to specify object implementations right.
We've come up with the objects in the system.
We understand what interfaces we need.
Now we need to actually go and implement.
Well this is a common problem obviously implementing solutions.
The implementation is defined design defined by the class.
You know that and it specifies the objects internal data and representation in defines the operations
that the object can perform.
All of these things are helped by understanding design patterns design patterns have high level implementation
that are gonna are gonna be descriptive scribed.
So these three problems are reduced and help a lot if you understand design patterns the multiple sets
you have available for you to you.
The easier it is going to be able to identify the objects specify the interfaces and do the actual implementation.
It's all about making you a better program or a high quality programmer and design patterns we'll do
that.
Problems of dust by design parents again continued determining object granulated.
So we know objects can be very large and you can have many many objects right.
Usually the more objects you have the harder it is to maintain if the objects are not cohesive and they
have a ton of code.
Again hard to maintain design patterns will provide that granularity.
They'll say how big should this object be how many objects should you have.
So the granularity can include size and number it also can represent everything down to the hardware
all the way up to the entire application.
So design patterns address this granular issue.
For example the facade pattern that we're going to learn about describes how you can represent complete
subsystems as objects.
So right there it's going to tell you this is how many objects you need for this subsystem the away
pattern we're going to.
It will describe how to support huge number of objects at the finest granularity.
Abstract Factory and builder are going to yield objects whose only responsibilities are creating other
objects right.
That's a level of granularity.
How do I create this object.
They identify that they have a common solution for that the visitor in the command will yield objects
was only responsibilities are to implement a request on another object or group of objects so they have
a single responsibility they're highly cohesive right in and again allows it easier to maintain the
design in the code.
To summarise design patterns advantages right.
They allow for software reuse where you reuse these high quality solutions to commonly recurring problems.
They also establish common terminology to improve communications with teams.
We've talked about that they shift the level of thinking to a hiring perspective you don't get bogged
down in the details when you're trying to solve a problem you first look at at a high level and then
you try to solve it and you get down the details when you need to get down to the details.
They decide whether you have the right design not just one that works right.
It's a high quality design again because it's been tried and tested.
It's the right design for that problem or for that situation.
Design Patterns also improve individual learning and team learning.
You can learn things quicker by understanding these concepts.
It improves the modifiable ability quality of code.
Code is constantly changing.
If the code is so tightly coupled and it's so hard to change every time you need to add something new
you're gonna break everything.
So if you can make your code adaptable to change it's going to be a big deal in design parents like
to do that.
They facilitate adoption of improved design alternatives even when patterns are not used explicitly.
So because of your knowledge base and because of the different solutions you have it allows you to come
up with other solutions other alternatives.
They discover alternatives to large inheritance hierarchy so it allows you to avoid using these gigantic
inheritance hierarchies that a lot of developers tend to overuse.
You can avoid that through the use of your experience with design patterns up to this point.
I've described a lot of theoretical approaches or through theoretical definitions design patterns.
What is the design pattern.
Why do we use it.
What are the advantages.
Soon we're gonna get into more practical solutions.
I'm going to talk more about Java code and more about design examples or implementation examples.
But again it's important early on to understand what you're studying.
Why do you want to study it.
Why is it important.
So the advantages and the definitions the high level overview I think is necessary.
If you're getting bored you can just jump right in to some coding examples and start right off with
some of the upcoming lectures on specific design patterns.
But if you really want to have a good while rounding rounded understanding of why you use design patterns
and the principles and strategies that you employ please stick with me.
Thank you.