Hello and welcome back.
This lecture I'd like to talk about the different types of design patterns so we mentioned before that
design patterns will vary in their granularity level of abstraction and how they relate to one another.
So there's different types of design patterns based on these characteristics.
Some patterns are often used together.
For example the composite pattern is often used with the iterator or the visitor Some patterns are alternatives.
They may do the same thing that they're just slightly differ.
So for example the prototype is often an alternative to the Abstract Factory pattern.
Again just on some examples some patterns result in similar designs even though the patterns have different
intents.
So some of the structure diagrams of the composite the decorator look very similar.
As we go through these different patterns I will provide you with different diagrams outlining the design.
And you'll notice these similarities so there are many design patterns and we need to organize them
based on all these differences and similarities.
All right.
If they're used together if there are alternatives if they have different intents but similar designs
we want to have a way to organize them.
So the design patterns are classified into families of related patterns.
And again this allows you to learn the patterns much quicker because you can focus your efforts on specific
patterns grouped together so the 23 design patterns that we're going to study in this class all have
these different levels of granularity and they all have specific applications that they can be adhered
to.
So they're divided into three different types the gangs of four came up with this classification they're
organized by purpose.
Basically what the pattern does is going to be how they're organized into these three different types
three types that are Oregon.
They're organized into our creation all structural structural and behavior creation all patterns concerned
the process of object creation so creating instances of objects in Java.
We do that using the new operator the structural patterns deal with the composition of classes or objects.
All right how classes are related to one another by using composition.
A lot of us has had use that has a characteristic behavior patterns are all organized in how objects
communicate how they interact.
So message passes in passing or how objects can work together.
Design Patterns are also organized by scope and what this means is whether the pattern applies primarily
to classes or to objects.
So this is sort of a subcategory based on those three categories creation all patterns will be sub to
class patterns or object patterns.
The same applies to structural and behavioral class patterns deal with relationships between classes
and their subclasses pretty straightforward.
These relate these relations is usually a stretch establish through inheritance or using an interface
through the inheritance child relationship objects patterns deal with objects relationships.
And this means they can be changed at runtime making them much more dynamic.
Right.
We you some kind of polymorphism or something like that.
They describe how objects can be composed into larger structures using object composition.
Right.
Taking a number of different objects making them and then creating another object that contains all
those objects.
Right.
So it's very very useful so we'll talk about these three different categories and then also talk about
how the class and object patterns also differ under those categories First we'll start with creation
patterns in basically the creation of pattern to have to deal with creating instances of objects.
And the reason for that is when you write a program the program should not depend on how the objects
are created or arranged.
You don't should have any dependencies in this in this regard regional design patterns provide a way
to create objects in Java.
As I mentioned the simplest way to create an instance of an object by using the new operator.
We all know this because we're we're pretty proficient in Java.
So for example if you were to create an instance of an object named Fred you create an object named
Fred equals new Fred.
Pretty straightforward.
That's an instance of the Fred class creation design patterns.
The abstract the instantiation process and again this is another common theme you're going to see in
many of the design patterns.
This concept of abstraction in what is the concept of abstraction it is hiding details.
You do not want to be bogged down with the details.
As a programmer you don't need to waste your time dealing with that.
So a lot of the details are hidden and in the case of creation patterns the creation of logic is hidden.
So all the knowledge is encapsulated about how the Concord classes are created and what concrete classes
an entire application will use.
So simply the programmer is probably gonna call a method or use another object rather than instantiating
those objects directly using the new operator.
So when you use these design patterns that are concerning creation patterns you're not going to be using
new.
You're going to be calling a method or you're going to use another object.
All the system at large knows about the objects is their interfaces as defined by abstract classes.
Again another common theme you're going to see throughout the course are these design pattern is going
to be implemented using interfaces and after our classes and a lot of times it's interchangeable.
There's not much difference to the interface in abstract class in Java an abstract class both an interface
and after class cannot be instantiated.
The only real differences in abstract class will have maybe some default behavior but even now with
Java eleven interface is going to have to fault behavior as well.
After our classes may have properties interfaces don't usually have properties so this gives the programmer
a lot of flexibility in what gets created who creates it how it gets created and winning gets created.
Right.
So this is important that this flexibility is provided by the programmer.
And again another common theme.
Flexibility so craziness patterns will let you can figure a system with product objects that vary widely
in structure and functionality.
The conflict collaboration can be static which is at compile time or dynamic which is at runtime sometimes
criminal patterns are competitors.
So for example there are cases with either a prototype or an abstract factory that can be used interchangeably
and they both will help the programmer sometimes creating all patterns are complementary.
What this means is you can use them together so the builder criminal pattern.
When we discuss that it can often be used with other patterns to implement which components get built.
The prototype can use a singleton design pattern in its implementation
creation or class patterns defer some part object creation of subclasses.
So remember I mentioned on a previous slide that each category reclassification of design pattern whether
it be creation all behavior or structural still has subcategories.
This class patterns versus object patterns.
And again the class patterns have to deal with classes and subclasses and so for creation all patterns
the class patterns will just defer the actual instantiation to the subclasses or if their interfaces
to any of the interface classes and implement the interface creation will object patterns D for the
stance taken to another object so they're going to the responsibility of another object instantiate.
There are five criminal patterns that we're going to study and focus on.
I gave you a brief glimpse of this in our course overview when we go through each pattern will identify
similarities and differences between these different criminal patterns.
The 5 creation patterns that we will study will be the factory the abstract factory the builder the
prototype and the singleton and we'll cover those and a lot more detail.
The second classification I want to talk about the structural patterns these patterns describe how classes
and objects can be combined to form larger structures where we use them together usually inheritance
is used with interfaces or implementations.
Again that's a common theme.
A structural object patterns describe ways to assemble objects.
So for example complex user interfaces and accounting data user interface may have many many different
objects such as buttons menus sub menus.
How can you use all of them together to create a user interface these design patterns concern class
and object composition.
Again composition.
You often see this will go through the details of composition book composition is all about a has a
relationship composition.
There's actually a composite pattern that's very similar to this composition is where one AMG contains
another object and it's usually described with two terms.
Aggregation in composition together interchangeably and it's really just whether or not the lifetime
of the object is this We'll talk about that again in more detail.
Specifically the composite design pattern describes how to build the class hierarchy made up of classes
for two kinds of objects.
And this describes really composition the proxy design pattern acts as a convenient surrogate or place
holder for another object.
Often using and networking just like if you think of a proxy with a web address it provides this level
of indirection to specific properties of objects.
There are 7 structural patterns that we will study we'll go through that again.
We're gonna be highlighting similarities and differences and have a ton of examples some examples of
those seven structural patterns are things like the adapter the composite.
As I mentioned the bridge or the facade.
The third classification of patterns that we'll discuss are the behavior patterns.
These are really the ones that you might me use most often because they talk about object communication
how objects relate to one another another and how they can basically talk to one another character.
They characterize complex control flow that is difficult to follow runtime control flow loop statements
iteration conditional statements they shift the focus away from flow of control to let you concentrate
just on the way the objects are interconnected.
Again a common theme of abstraction flexibility you'd want to worry about a lot of these details these
patterns will do them for you.
So these patterns increase flexibility in carrying out this communication they provide solutions on
how to segregate objects to be both dependent and independent.
They're concerned with algorithms and the assignment of responsibilities between optics.
Again this will all be clear when we go through more examples and more details of each one of our patterns
the behavior patterns use inheritance.
Again commonality here to describe these algorithms flow control inheritance does include interfaces
for example the template method is a design pattern that's behavior and it's an abstract definition
of an algorithm it defines an algorithm step by step and lets you interchange some of those steps a
subclass will flush out the actual algorithm by defining abstract operations so you have an abstract
class and then each one of those abstract implementations it needs need to be separated out will be
in their own subclasses behavior object patterns describe how a group of objects cooperate to perform
a task that no single object can carry out alone.
So again object composition is used rather than inheritance both and both times when you use these object
patterns.
Right so remember the difference here we're identifying differences between class and object patterns
class patterns we know use inheritance object patterns use composition but specifically related to behavior
patterns.
What will happen in the object patterns is how the group evolves cooperate form a single task again
composition is preferred over inheritance with the object patterns the mediator patterns example of
an object pattern under the behavior classification uses a mediator objects for pure object communication
mediator basically has this level of indirection that allows for loose coupling.
Another important term again I'm trying to identify highlight some of these terms that you hear throughout
the course coupling coupling all about dependencies tightly coupled systems harder to maintain.
Because if you change one class or another class gets affected we want to avoid tightly coupled systems
of tightly coupled objects.
We want to strive for loose coupling related to cohesion.
Right.
We know cohesion talks about responsibility.
Focus of an object.
High cohesion means that the object is very very highly focused.
It's not all over the place like cohesion would be.
An object has too many responsibilities it's doing too many things.
And again this relates to maintenance fixing bugs adding new code.
It's much harder to do that in a system that is tightly coupled and very low low cohesion there are
11 behaviour patterns that we will study things like the chain of response the command the interpreter.
Many more patterns in the behavior aspect.
The last slide here I wanted to show you is just really an overview I took from the getting a fourth
book.
That kind of identifies these three different classifications and a quick summary of what's going on.
This is just for reference.
Again we're gonna go through all these details when we talk about each pattern in detail but you'll
notice how each one is separated.
Again creation all patterns right.
How you create instance of objects either using objects themselves or composition after factory builder
factory method they vary a little bit and they also have some similarities and sometimes they work together
structural patterns like the adapter and the decorator right have to do with the structure of an object.
Behavior patterns how they can communicate mediate or momento all are categorized based on what they
can accomplish.
And so this is how the course is going to be designed we're going to go through each one of these patterns
sequentially by focusing on each category first.