Hi class Welcome back.
This lecture I wanna talk about selecting and using design patterns gives you an idea of what design
pattern should I use and what's specific situation.
So let's talk a little bit about overview in terms of software design approaches.
Before we talk about how to select things.
So normally when you design software it's a process of putting things together right.
A common approach is to look immediately for objects in classes and components and then think about
how they should fit together.
You identify the objects get all the classes together get the components together and then say Oh how
are they related.
How are we going to put them together so that we can work together.
That's typically how you do it.
That's not a great approach.
It's not very organized.
A better approach is to use one that's based on design patterns and you notice as we talk about design
patterns that you know just with the title design patterns that they're heavily related to design.
So in order to understand design patterns you first have to understand at least some high level components
of design and that's why in the beginning class we focus on that a little bit.
So with design patterns you start out with a conceptual understanding of the whole.
In order to understand what needs to be accomplished you know you kind of look at a high level you say
okay let's look at a conceptual level you identify the patterns that are present in the whole you think
about your problem in terms of the patterns that are present.
The purpose of the pattern is to define relationships among these different entities you start with
those patterns that create the context for the others.
That's your first approach you identify these patterns you look at the whole and then you start with
the specific patterns to create the context for the other
you then work inward from the context you look at the remaining patterns in any other patterns that
you might have uncovered you pick the patterns that define the context for the patterns that would remain
and then you repeat this cycle over and over and over again the repetition is again identify the patterns
that are present the whole start with those patterns that could create the context for the others and
then work inward from that context when you're done doing that over and over and over again where you
have all the patterns identified you then try to do some refining you find the design and you implement
within the context created by applying the patterns one at a time as you refine you always consider
the context implied by the patterns the implementation incorporates details dictated by the patterns
and this will be much more intuitive when we go through the implementation of each pattern when we attack
a big system and try to identify the patterns in the systems.
So not only do design patterns help you with specific smaller set of problems they can also help you
with a high level conceptual design by identifying patterns as a whole and then working your way through
it.
You don't always have to do this but this does help as opposed to just getting all these objects trying
to figure out how those objects work together.
Think of it in terms of design patterns.
Designing by adding concepts within the context of previously presenting concepts is attainable.
Well many of these patterns create robust software because they define context within which the classes
that implement them can work.
So I just wanted to talk about that real quickly that design patterns can help with your overall design
approach by looking at design parents conceptually so when you become an expert in design patterns you
understand all these different criminal behavior structural patterns that can help you become a better
designer because now you can think of terms of design patterns when designing a system as a whole.
There is more than 20 design patterns that we're going to study right.
Twenty three.
It's gonna be hard to find the one that addresses a particular design problem.
If you don't have a lot experience experience is gonna be the key.
Once you gain more and more experience it's going to be easier to choose which one in a specific situation.
There are different approaches to finding design pattern for the right problem.
You can consider how design patterns solve design problems so you can just look at the solutions and
then you can determine the object granularity of different kinds of patterns based on the solution.
You can see the interfaces that each pattern specifies with objects.
Understanding these concepts can help guide your search for the right pattern by looking at the solutions
looking at the interfaces in the solutions and the granularity of the solutions or you can look at the
intent the intent of the pattern.
What's really the purpose that can tell you exactly what pattern use in a given situation and the intent.
As I mentioned in earlier lectures that is always provided with the pattern itself.
You can identify if the intent is relevant to your problem and if it is you would use that pattern so
you can start by looking at the different classifications criminal structural behavior narrow down your
search based on the intent of those patterns whether or not you're going to create instances whether
or not the objects need to communicate from there.
You can look at each one of the patterns intent purpose and identify the pattern that way.
So first you can look at a higher level look at the solutions or you can look at the intent.
Another way to identify a pattern for a given situation is you can look how the patterns in or relate
to one another.
So if you understand the relationships between different patterns that can help direct you direct you
to the right pattern or at least the group patterns study you can study the patterns that have a like
purpose kind of it kind of forces you to do that through the classifications and then once you know
the like purposes you can identify the similarities and differences because sometimes you're going to
come down and you're gonna say okay I got it down to these two patterns.
The prototype and the Singleton but they're very similar so which one should I use.
That's when you look at similarities differences and you say Okay I think in this this situation the
prototype is going to work a little bit better than the Singleton.
So look at the purpose and similarities and differences choosing a pattern can cause examine the cause
of the redesign.
So if you determine why you're actually changing the design that you currently have.
If you're redesigning or refactoring you can look at that.
The cause of the redesign and that can help point you in the right direction.
So you find any issues in your problem that may cause a redesign.
Look at the patterns that help you avoid the causes of this redesign.
And then then you want to redesign it and it can point you in the right direction.
Consider what should what should be variable in your design variable means what changes what changes
in your design.
If you look at it your entire design and all the different objects which particular component is needed
most change doesn't change most often it's constantly changing that might be the right place to apply
a pattern.
This approach focuses on the on the causes the opposite of the causes right.
In the previous approach you can look at the cause of the redesign and say OK.
This is what I need to do in this approach you're actually looking at trying to identify beforehand
what are all the changes before you redesign.
And then that way you don't have to redesign if you pick patterns that allow for modify ability then
that reduces the redesign.
So what this does is you consider what you want to be able to change without doing a redesign.
The focus here is on encapsulating the concept that varies a theme of many design patterns design patterns
are going to allow for out of ability and so they're going to be very very isolated.
They're going to be loosely coupled so that when you want to add new things or you want to change the
existing things you don't affect a lot of different objects as far as once you understand what pattern
you want to you picked out the pattern that you think you need to use.
Well how do you actually use it to apply it.
So once you pick the pattern how do you use it.
You want to read the pattern once once through for an overview.
Right.
Maybe if you're not an expert in design patterns you need to refresh your memory.
Look at the pattern.
Read it over through for never you pay particular attention to the applicability in the consequences
of the pattern.
Remember we talked earlier about the common all patterns have they have a name.
Right they have an intent.
Consequences usually deal with advantages or disadvantages drawbacks.
When you look at this information in an overview that can tell you what you do with the pattern and
that will also ensure that the pattern that you picked is right for your pattern.
You want to kind of do a double check because once you actually identify the pattern you said this pattern
is right approach.
You want to look at the actual advantages and draw back because sometimes there's tradeoffs you then
go back and you study the structure of the participants and the collaboration of the pattern the structure
has to do with essentially the class diagram how the objects relate to one another whether that you
know the interfaces and subclasses and so forth.
The participants are names given to specific components of the structure and then the collaborations
are again how they work together.
You want to make sure you understand the design completely concerning the classes and objects and how
they relate to one another.
Right.
When you actually want to use it you know and we're going to all go through this in this class.
So this should be second hand but you need to understand this before you actually apply a pattern.
You want to look at sample code to see a concrete example of the pattern in code.
This will also help you become more comfortable with applying the pattern studying the code helps you
learn how to implement the pattern and you'll notice that as I go through the slide this is exactly
what we're going to do in our class.
You followed up with defining specific classes.
This includes any interfaces any inheritance relationships any aggregation of composition any instance
variables that represent data and object references inside the class.
You also can identify existing classes in your application that the pattern will effect.
Usually this is minimal because patterns are designed to be loosely coupled.
But when you do add a new pattern into an existing system make sure any of the dependencies or any things
that you're changing and makes you modify them accordingly to have minimal impact
you also have to choose names for the pattern participants that are meaningful in the application context.
So this is useful to incorporate the participant name into the name that appears in the application
right.
So this really just has to do with naming when you actually apply the pattern make sure you write use
good names for your classes and objects.
The best way to do this is when you look at the documentation for the pattern.
Look at the participants the participants identify really names that you should use.
So for example and in a builder you know you would maybe have a class that is is the builder class or
abstract builder would be the abstract class.
I mean it's usually very intuitive but sometimes some patterns have specific components or specific
names corresponding to the participants.
Another example would be the visitor has the visitor abstract class and then the visit T or.
And then also has a component named elements that you would use when you're designing your examples.
So the participant name is very important when you want to do your naming.
It just helps the pattern more explicit any actual implementation.
This goes.
This really has to do with all naming and all of your objects.
Another example here I provide is a strategy pattern for a text composing algorithm you might have classes
like simple layout strategy or text layout strategy.
Incorporate the names of the design pattern into your presentation as well as specific participants
into the implementation of the design pattern itself.
Define application specific names for operations in the pattern.
Use the responsibilities and collaborations associated with EAP operation as a guide.
Again we're going to go through the patterns you're going to see these responsibilities collaboration
work that into your code when you apply the pattern be consistent in your naming conventions.
You might use the Create prefix can't consistently to denote a factory method for example it's pretty
straightforward stuff but it's it's things that you have to focus on to write high quality code.
And as I mentioned high quality code is a specific aim and goal for this class.
You then want to implement the operations to carry out the responsibilities and collaboration in the
pattern.
And again you can do this efficiently by looking at coding examples.
We all do this even the experts will look at some examples to guide us but this is what how you want
to use and apply a pattern you want to go through these specific steps knowing the correct way to choose
a pattern to identify patterns and look at a design at a high level.
I want to tell you not want to tell you what you should not be doing.
So when you try to pick up a design pattern things that you shouldn't do you shouldn't just apply them
indiscriminately.
Again kind of a no brainer but just don't throw it in there and say oh here I am.
I want to use the singleton because I'm a big fan of singletons and I'm just gonna throw it in there.
Well it might not be useful it may complicate things.
Patterns often achieve flexibility and variability by true introducing additional levels of an interaction.
So although the pattern simplify things some of them may be complicated and they may actually use a
lot of objects and a lot of inheritance to provide this flexibility abstraction and variability.
But knowing that there can be tradeoffs whenever you add new levels or new design there are tradeoffs.
So sometimes the patterns can complicate the design or they can cost you some performance.
Again the advantages you're using a pattern and it's helping you a lot with flexibility and variability
but it may be a little complicated or maybe costing you performance you want to be careful with that.
So you want to make sure you look at that in order in terms of that tradeoff.
A design pattern should only be applied when the flexibility it affords is actually needed.
Don't add flexibility just flexibility sake if your code is already some more flexible flexible.
Don't try to make it more flexible it doesn't necessarily need to be.
You have to understand these specific details understand when the flexibility is needed.
The consequences of the design pattern are most helpful when evaluating patterns benefits and liabilities
consequences really are just that the benefits and liabilities you want to look at those to make sure
that you're not actually making the system again more complicated or more.
You know that tradeoff is worse off I just wanted to provide a quick overview of design patterns in
terms of how you can use and apply a design pattern.
Thank you.