Hello and welcome back here we're going to have a look at the Jenkyns you guys so you can get used to
this because we're going to be using these a lot.
So let's give the admin user that we created 1 2 3 4 for the password.
And let's click on the kibbitzing bottom line again and then you're going to see this screen for the
Jenkyns dashboard.
OK this is perfect.
So here we are.
And let me introduce you to Jenkin's dash for it and we have here a lot of options that we're going
to look in the future in these cores.
So here you have an icon which is for creating new items new tasks and more.
We have a lot of styles here.
Don't worry we will have sections for days.
Here we have people it means who is actually allowed to log in to do things to create jobs to deliver
jobs where you can configure everything and you are going to learn how to create users restrict permissions
and more.
Here we have a real history.
Our tasks have histories So here we're going to see the performance we're going to see how many tests
fail how many task when succeeded and more.
So here we have managed Jenkin's icon.
We have more things don't worry about this error we're going to fix it in the future.
This is because our DNA is here we have the system we have things for it.
Configuring security for configuring credentials to install plugins.
We have a lot of things here and we're going to go through all of these in decors.
So here we have more things like credentials to manage sensitive data like passwords keys or more and
well I think this is that.
Q summarize for the Jenkins dashboard.
So in the next video we're going to start playing around with all of this items and we're going to learn
how to use them.
So see you in the next lesson.