Hello and welcome back OK in this video we're going to create our first map.
It's not going to be your job.
It's going to be pretty simple because it's our first job in the future we're going to do more interesting
things.
So to create a job we can either click here or create a new item.
So let's click on to create new item and now we need to give it a name.
So let's say that we want this job to be called my first job.
That was my first job.
We're going to click and freestyle project which is a simple project and we click OK.
After this you're going to see there's a screen with all of these can be green.
Don't worry I know it could be like overwhelming or something but it's pretty simple.
So the first thing that we're going to do or a difference in that I want you to keep in mind is that
a task is in Jenkin's called a job.
So you're probably going to see everywhere people using the concept of job in a job is nothing but a
task something that is going to be done.
That's a job.
So we're configuring here a job or a task.
But the concept in Jenkyns is a job.
So here in the Bills section we're going to build Stabb and we're going to look for execute command.
So I want to show you one thing and this is that these shil refers to our virtual machine but not entirely
to our virtual machine.
Remember that we created at container in here and these container actually has the Jenkin's service
up and running.
But if we look in our machine I mean outside of the container there is no Jenkin's server.
We don't even have Java installed as you can see.
But if we go inside of their container doing the correct section Dashti Jenkin's and asking for a bus
terminal we hit enter and if we type Java you are going to see that we have Javins or heater we can
even do a Java Dasch version and we have a Java insult within the container.
So let's make this clear.
We have our virtual machine which is nothing else but like the house of that container and that container
which can be placed using Dr APF is the service itself.
So as you can see when we do our Duckery except the terminal actually changes it's a perience.
For example in the creative file coach Hello slash stamp slash hello you're going to see that this file
is is going to be created only within that container.
Hello.
But if we go out of that container and we look for the same file these file doesn't exist.
So please keep in mind that everything that's going to happen and.
Jenkins Yup we'll look cure within their container.
I mean we've seen the darker expect Dashti.
It's not going to happen outside.
Not here but everything up would around every command anything is going to be running within that container.
It's time to start running our job.
So let's say echo Hello world which is you know the most popular cool for beginners in technology.
So let's click on Save here in after we say if that's click on.
Now they're built but on means viewed in a project so for now if we go here.
Console output we are going to see that our job executed took says Phlip printin.
Hello world.
So remember what we just did is to create and configure Jopp.
We added it step here as show step and then we said take him in kill hill work.
We saved this and then we clicked on the Beeld Nah burning.
So here we have a bill history we can just go into the number of the execution that we want to know.
Click on the console.
And then we have these output which means that the job executed correctly.
So you already created your first.
Yup cool.
Remember these job has been executed within the container not outside.
So having said this.
See you in the next lesson.