Kilo and work him back.
So in this video we're going to be playing weed our job off they job that we created in the previous
lesson.
And I just wanted to tell you that you can go to the Jenkin's home whenever you want.
Clicking on the Jenkin's button here.
So we're going to click in the name of our job and we're going to go into the configure section.
And as you can see we're again presented with this a screen that has all of that configuration.
And this is our current configuration.
So we're going to make this job more dynamic.
In Linux we have a cool command which is the date command.
So let's head to our virtual machine let's go inside of that container.
Remember that we are outside of the container because if we type Ducker P.S. We can see the container.
So we're going to go to the container except Dashti.
Jenkins Bash and here we are within the container as you can see.
This crane looks different.
So if we type in the date command here as you can see we have an output and that output is nothing else
but the current date and time.
So there is actually that it returns day command.
But what happens if you want to execute this command and I want to have text with this command for example
I want to say the date is and then I want that result of these date.
So how do I do this in Linux.
That's pretty easy employ you use the echo command and then you type your string like for example current
date is and then you want to execute the commands.
How do you execute the command.
You put Azango are here and then you put parentheses within the parentheses.
You'd type the command through on is good for example.
And as you can see it say it's current date is and it returns the value of the date.
Come on.
Which is pretty useful for doing whatever you want to.
I could say a note or a command like QMI for example and they could change.
You know they command and I want to say who am I.
For example.
And as you can see it's actually given the same text but returning different values based on the command
that I'm executing here.
So let's keep it like this with the date current date is this that's a current date and time cool.
So this command is actually awesome So we're going to copy this command.
And as you saw here on the job definition we have a shell.
So this is actually the same shell as this one so you can freely copy and paste the command that we
typed in the previous terminal in this terminal.
And this is going to work the same way.
So let's click on the safe and once you have that configure you click on Bill now and then you go to
that job.
Console output and then you see the output of the is which says current time current date and time is
the output of Dick Kamen.
Cool isn't it.
So for example here you are saying at 37 which is the second.
So let's hit big old ones again and let's see if there is any difference.
Where are you going to go here into debil history.
Job number four.
Click on console output and heater.
We're going to see that the day actually change the second change so there's means that Jenkyns is actually
being execute in their command.
Whenever we ask for it.
So this is pretty cool.
You already know how to use linux command within your.
Jenkins Yup and printed with text which is pretty useful sometimes.
So I'll see you in the next lesson.