Hello and welcome back in this video we're going to learn how to redirect output in Jenkyns.
So in bash remember that you are going to be working with bash because in the job definition if we go
to configure what do you find as shell so shell is exactly the same thing that you are.
BASH command please.
Again remember that we are within the container.
So if you are not within the container go ahead and jump into a container with these commands.
Cool.
So now in bash we can use barrel's a variable is nothing like name.
And for example my name Ricardo.
So if I now do an echo for a name I will have these balloting here.
We want our shell to say Hello Ricardo the date and time is the output of the date.
C'mon how do we do this.
Pretty simple.
We do an echo and we say for example favorable with US dollars in here which is the variable that would
you vyne up your name.
So we say hello to the name and then we say the current That's the current date and time is the output
of the date.
Come on.
Pretty cool isn't it.
So we already knew how to do it is.
But this is something new using variables in bash.
OK.
Nice.
If we copy and paste these for Howard Jenkins job this is going to look exactly the same thing.
Oh but probably this is going to fail here because the variable doesn't exist.
So we need to define the variable map here.
Same name equals to Ricardo.
Cool.
So as you can see this is exactly the same content that we wrote on our terminal.
So if you want to test a Jenkin's job before running the job itself you can copy and paste the comments
to your terminal normally.
OK.
So let's save this and let's execute this job.
So we click on build now and we are going to see what happened.
So if we head to the Butte history to the last execution console output we're going to see the output
that we were expecting.
So it says Hello Ricardo.
Current date and time is the output of the date.
Come on.
Pretty cool.
But now what happens if you want to redirect that data into a fire.
How do we do this.
That's pretty simple.
We put design which is a redirections signing bash and then we give it a pad like for example Tam and
we say in full for example here ENTRAR.
And as you can see nothing comes in determiners our response.
But if we take a look on these file cats lasht damps lashed in full.
We're going to see the content within the file itself.
So this is pretty cool and we're going to do this from Jenkyns So let's remove the file that we just
created and if we do a cat to this file the file is no longer available because we already deleted it.
So now let's copy this command for the shell in here.
Let's click can configure let's delete our current configuration and let's pays the new one.
And as you can see we're redirecting these into a fight.
So OK let's click on safe and let's click on build.
Now if you see the built get to go to their number console output and as you can see the job actually
finish as it sits.
So now let's go to our container and let's look for a data file.
And as you can see it is perfect.
The file is actually being created from our Jenkin's job.
So for example if I removed the file again I do I cut the file doesn't exist anymore.
Verify Beeld.
Now the job.
Once again it's going to be Mark as succeeded.
And if we open the console output it says success and if we take calls on the file the file already
exists because the job created and this is the important part about it wanting to tell you as we're
using docker to host the service all of the files that we created are going to be saved within their
containers.
So if we go out of the container and we look on CAD temp info we don't have that file because it's a
completely different file system.
But if we go within that container then we have a fire that's cool.
And remember that you're Jenkin's container is a completely isolated process with it's sound or Purton
system in Linux distributions or that's why you can't see the file on your host.
But don't worry to solve that if you want to share files with your hosts.
You can use volume's we're going to see that later.
But don't worry for now.
Just keep in mind that the files that you are creating are being created within the container and if
you go outside of the container you are not going to find those files.
So this is said Ferdie's video.
See you in the next lesson.