Hello and welcome back in this video we're going to learn how to execute on the script.
JENKINS So to achieve this.
The first thing that we need to do is of course to create in a script.
So let's head into our virtual machine.
Remember that in this case we we're outside of that container because we're going to create a sample
file.
So if we go inside of the container as we have learned this way and then we type B which is a text editor
we're going to have a natter and this is the because containers normally only half what they need.
So for example in this case Jenkin's only half packet is triggered into Jenkin's shooting have any order
package like network tools or elders because a container is meant to do only what it is meant to do.
That's why we're going to log out of the container and we're going to create the file here outside of
the container.
So let's create a simple script which can be code like a script that is age and remember that to type
in Pudi you need to press the letter I call.
So normally in Linux or when we are creating the scripts the first line informs which interpreter are
we going to use.
In this case we're going to use bash.
So that's why we're marking has been bashed.
So let's start with a sample script that is going to accept parameters and it's going to print out the
name and the last thing for one person.
So these would be like a..
Hello.
And then it's going to receive the name of one person and then that last name of that person.
So if we exit this is crap like this what do you think that's going to happen if I just go ahead and
you and I try to execute this script.
I will have.
The first error here.
OK to fix this we need to give executable permissions to fire and to do so we need to execute a command
change mode plus X which is going to give executable permissions to the file to then try again.
And you are going to see it.
The only one thing that comes is the helo.
So what we want to do is like for example we are going to call this a crib like this.
And then I want to pass my name and my last name in the script.
So this in this case should print these BERNHOLZ saying hello name and last names respectively.
So let's modify our script and lead at pedometers.
So in Bashan rhomboid parameters are represented with a dollar sign number one for the first parameter
dollar sign.
Number two the second parameter.
So on and so forth.
So in this case we're going to say that the variable name that we are mentioning here is going to be
a reference of the first parameter.
Cool.
So we're going to say that the last name that we're referencing heater it's going to be the Valley of
the second parameter that we are going to reset.
So that's like this.
And OK let's save this and let's execute this crypt again.
And as you can see cool it's actually it returning devalues that we are passing to the script itself
to cool.
Now if we want to execute this from Jenkins What do you think we need to do.
As I told you we are outside of the container which is completely isolated and different file system.
So our container can't see this file unless we copy that file to the container in the future.
We're going to learn how to use volumes and Ducrot to share data between the host and the container.
But for now that's just go ahead and copy the files that we just created to the container.
So for example let's say that we want to copy the file which is called the script that SH.
So we got Kurt C.P the name of the file that we want to copy.
Then the name of that container where we want a copy.
And then we put a call on and the full path.
So let's say that we want this to be call slushed slash script that is default pop.
So if we hit enter and then we go inside of a container like this and we take Culligan Tam script which
is the location that we defined before we are going to find easing here.
Pretty cool.
So we have our script here.
So how do we execute this cool.
We just take this full path and executed inside of the container.
And we are going to have an empty answer as you can see because we're not passing any promotors.
If we pass this then we're going to have both of the parameters in here.
So cool let's copy D-pad for a script.
Let's go to our job.
Let's click on configure and let's execute that as crib from the Jenkins shil.
Do you know how to do it so if you want do it before I do it otherwise I'm just going to do it right
away.
So it's going to be pretty simple as simple as it is we're just going to copy and paste this the path
and then we're going to pass the parameters.
Simple as that.
So you can just click here on safe and then if we build now what it's going to happen.
The Jenkyns is going to go to the file read this crap and it's going to pass the parameters that we
are passing in the shell and in the output as you can see we have the expected output.
Cool.
So again what happened here.
Jenkins from its shell actually took the parameters that we passed and dread them and at the same time
passed those parameters to the script.
We can do it pairs in various roles as well.
So we could say like name equal to my name and we could say last name equals to my last name and then
what we're going to pass here are diverse.
So we say like name and last name as you can see here.
And the output should be exactly the same.
So let's go ahead and save it.
Let go and click on the build button.
And as you can see we have an error here which is pretty cool.
We made a typo and what is that typo.
Can you spot it.
So the type it's pretty simple.
We define as easy here.
We're given variables but in this case we have any space here which is a problem.
So if we go ahead and fix that and then we click on safe and then we build it.
Now we're going to see that this is going to be blue again.
So what happens in Jenkins is that whenever an execution fails the caller of the real history it's going
to be red and it's going to be marked as failure.
But if it doesn't fail then it's going to be marked as X's and the color is going to be blue.
If we go into it comes out here and we take a look on the response we can see that we're defining the
variable name the variable last name of that we're passing those variables as parameters to our main
script.
And then the output is exactly as we were expecting which is pretty cool.
So OK this is it first is what you see in the next lesson.