Hello and welcome back in this video we're going to learn how to create a list pedometer in our Jenkin's
job.
So whenever we come to build but it's going to show up at least we can choose the value that we want.
So two are any parameter we click the Add parameter button and we choose.
In this case choice pedometer.
So we're going to give it a name which can be like last name for example any humor.
We're going to give choices.
So let's say the first last name is going to be like Smith.
Second one is going to be my last name.
One is going to be our random one and that's it.
Cool here in this case we have a parameter which is called last name in the list of values.
So depending on which value they use or picks up then these variables are going to take that value.
So let's make it clearer for example.
Now we have the first name now we have the second name.
And now what we need to do here is say like last name.
So let's save this and let's click can be permanent as you can see here we still have the first name
parameter which is a String parameter.
SECOND NAME IS the string parameters.
Well but if you want the last name that we just create is a list and if we click on this list we are
going to see the allowed Balios that we created before.
So the user can only choose one of these values.
So let's go ahead and use the last one.
And as you can see let's just give a random name here and click on Byard once the execution finishes
you are going to go here.
Cancel our booth and then you are going to see your hello.
The first parameter second Paramor and a third parameter that is the result of they choose another option
by that user.
So as you could see we choose they do last name as the value for this parameter so let's click for example
in this let's hit built in after the execution finishes we're going to go into the output.
And as you can see here this group is actually taking the values that we are sending which is pretty
good.
So cool.
You already know how to create a string parameters.
How to you create list parameters and how to make your Jenkyns job to print those values.
This is pretty cool.
SEE YOU IN THE NEXT LIST.
And.