Hello and welcome back in this video we're going to make things harder.
I mean now we're going to apply a little bit of logic to on the script.
So we're going to have conditions.
So the first thing that we're going to do is that we're going to if you're in the container Let's go
out of the container and let's keep modifying this crib that we created before.
So here we're going to add a third pedometer which is going to be like show and then the thing is that
these pedometer it's going to be a boolean value.
So it could be true or false.
And then we're going to say if this parameter is true then you are going to print the name and the last
name for that person.
Let me show you here.
If we go ahead and configure our JOP and we add a new parameter which is going to be boolean parameter
you can see that this is going to ask you for a name.
So we're going to name a shoe.
And the default value if we mark this it's going to be true if we don't mark this it's going to be false.
Right.
So this is what we're doing here.
We're saying show it's going to be Vishu.
These parameter that we are passing here we're going to delete this second name here.
We're only going to use three parameters Ferdie's BDO.
We're going to use the first name of the person the last name which is a list and then the show parameter
which is a Boolean parameter.
So OK we have here the name remembered Remember we already know how to pass parameters to on a script.
So in this case as Loizzo before this is going to be the first parameter second parameter and third
pedometer.
So we're going to apply a little bit of logic here and we're going to say f the variable show.
So we say like this equals two I'm just going to put it in zero on the string.
I don't remember how that comes from Jenkins.
Let's design a string and then let's say Van echo Hello.
Name a last name.
So what are we doing here.
We are as kin if the verbal issue which is the third parameter is equal to true.
Then we are going to print the name and the last name.
But what happens if this condition doesn't meet then we do our nails here and we are going to print
never.
So we're going to say something like If you want to see the name then the
PLEASE CHOOSE THE SHOW option please.
Let's see.
Please Mark.
Sure.
Option.
Ok cool.
And then we close the F here.
Nice.
So if we now execute these scrape What do you think that is going to happen.
Well the first thing that is going to happen is that these guys strainers if you want to say the name
please mark the show option but we don't have any.
Show up here but don't worry because this is is going to be executed from Jenkins.
So what happens if we pass here and name him and if we pass the last name and if we pass falls this
is we're going to see if you want to see the name please mark to show option.
Ok but what happens if we pass here.
True.
What you see is that now this creep is printing the name because the condition is been met.
And in this case the third parameter that show parameter is true.
So let me show you this creep once again and this is our logic.
So remember that here in Jenkin's we have just created at parameter within name of show which is going
to be the third parameter for our script and the default value for this case is going to be true because
we mark this if we just uncheck this and it's going to become.
So let's keep it like true.
And now the hours crib is working good.
We're going to copy this script to our container remember that we're outside of the containers so let's
keep this to the same location as before.
So if you hit CON-TROLL and the key are at the same time you're going to have something like filtering
here for searching.
Then you can type like C.P and you're going to have one command related to your input.
So in this case we want to do this again copy descript that we created or that we modify to the Jenkin's
container in this path.
So let's copy this.
Let's go ahead and exec into the container and let's look for a temp script.
And as you can see all our modifications are in place.
So cool let's go ahead and then let's see how the execution would look like we're in it to execute these
full path then pass one parameter to parameters and three parameters.
Q If we don't pass the third parameter or if we proceed as false then it's not going to show it nice.
So we're going to do this we're going to copy these thing here and we're going to pay this in artwork
shell.
So this is our script then.
This is not going to be my name.
This is going to refer to the name of the first parameter which is named know it's first name.
The first parameter that is coming from Jenkyns.
So let's say learn sign first name and then this is going to be the last name the name of the parameter
remembers or we're going to choose this and we're going to pay is using here.
And then these falls is going to be nothing else but this show pedometer.
So we go here do a lot of science and show.
So remember this is the first parameter that we're defining and not on our script.
If we do a cat tamps script you're going to see that name for its parameter last name second parameter
and show third parameter first second and third.
It's pretty cool.
OK so now we click on the safe that we can build with parameters.
So as you can see now we have the first name which is a string parameter and we can call it like John.
And then we have the last name that we can say do for example from the list.
And then we have this show so remember when you mark this this is going to be true when you don't mark
this this is going to be.
So in this case let's keep it like folds and let's hit the Beeld button.
And once the execution finishes you're going to go to the number console output.
And then you are going to see the error here which says if you want to see the name please mark the
show option.
OK.
So we're going to execute it back.
We're going to mark this show option.
We're going to choose a random last name from here.
Click on the build button and once the execution finishes we can go to the number console output and
Magique you have here your output.
Hello your name and your last name.
So remember that everything has been handled by this crypt.
The only one thing that Jenkins is doing is providing Debelle used to populate this information and
then based on the logic that we've viewed here then Jenkins is going to display whatever we want to
beat his play.
So this is pretty cool.
You already know how to create some parameters like strappings lists booleans.
Now you know how to integrate all of those parameters.
Now you know how to create a script and include those parameters so you can retrieve the value from
Jenkin and then pass those values to your script.
That is pretty cool for now.
So see you in the next lesson.