Hello and welcome to these Jenkin's course we are and have yet to get or learn in Jenkin's through all
the entire tar course.
So OK the first thing that we're going to do is that we're going to look for the Jenkin's page here.
Can I do Jenkins and then we have the page here which is Jenkin's that you and we are going to click
on.
You can see this is the page of the of Jenkin's itself.
So if we're going to be learning Jenkin's through the course I think that it's important to know why
it is.
Jenkins of course we need to know.
So as you can see here Jenkins is the leading Open-Source automation server.
So what is Jenkyns.
Well first simplicity we can say the Jenkin's is purely an odd mation server as you are reading here
and what is an automation server.
Of course it works to automate everything that you want.
Anything you want You can't out of my dad with Jenkins of course these days.
Jenkins is being used a lot for a continuous integration and for continuous delivery.
Don't worry about that yet.
We're going to have an entire section for learning continuous integration and continuous delivery.
But for now keep in mind that you can use Jenkin's to automate anything that you want.
OK.
So through the course of learning how to integrate Jenkin's with Dr. Inzi ball Amazon Web Services get
Mavin a how to create pipelines continuous integration continuos delivery the zeal in more.
So these are all in more is waiting for us through the entire inquiries.
Don't worry you have never used these tools before.
Like if Loker or Amazon or ansible.
Don't worry because we're going to be covering that and we're going to be explaining how to use them
and how to integrate them with Jenkyns.
So this and more I'll see you in the next lesson.