Hello and welcome back in this video we're going to start our service our container using doctored to
spin up the Jenkin's service.
So so far we already created the doc recomposed file and we created a directory here where we're going
to save all the files.
So remember that we define a volume here and we're saying OK Doctor please.
Everything that is within the container in this location please save this in this folder and this folder
means this folder.
So if we take a look on the folder itself we see that we don't have any data yet and that's normal because
we haven't created anything.
So please make sure the DS folder has proper permissions so Jenkyns can write.
And what do I mean by a proper permissions.
Make sure that that user 1000 can write to these folder.
And what's the use at 1000.
So in Linux we have IDs and as you can see these user Jenkin's user has the user id of 1000.
So we're going to do a suit to change our 1000 call on 1000 into these folder.
So Jenkin's harm we're going to do it recursively.
So OK when you leave this you will do an L L and you are going to see that the user the Downer's Jenkyns
and the group is Jenkyns.
This is because the container uses the ID law of to write to any of you have an order ID you are going
to probably have a never.
So please make sure that you read this command before is pinning up your server.
So okay we're really gave it permissions.
We only need to do this once.
I mean this time in no more.
And once we gave permissions were going to pin up this server doing a daquiri compose app Dashti and
what is going to happen here is the doctor is going to create the service reading the doc recomposed
the Phoenician theater and if we type.
Dr. Pierce we're going to see this server running here.
So this is it daquiri container behalf as Pan up our server using Duckery.
You can list your containers using daquiri.
P.
So as you can see this is actually working like a charm.
Cool.
I will type doc Curlylocks dash F and this is going to show me the locks for ascertaining container.
Remember that in our definition of the Dockerty composed file we said that the container name is Jenkin's
So we do a darker loves dash.
And if Jenkins we hit enter and as you can see here this is what we are hash.
We're going to use these later.
So for now what we're going to do is we're going to hit the IP address of our machine.
Do you remember the IP address.
So we're going to grab this IP we can pick up here from you remember we can click here.
Load and then we will have the AP.
So we're going to copy these IP and we're going to paste it into our browser so we paste it.
And we're going to have an error.
But if we do a call on ADHD and then we hit enter it again we are going to be a press centered on the
screen that tells us hey I am Jane.
Well finally we have Jenkyns installed and Jenkins wants to make sure that we are the owners.
So we need to introduce your password.
What's the password.
Well the password is pretty simple.
You go to put me here.
You do a duck Curlylocks dash F and you will see the password in here.
So this is the password and or even a copy of this.
Remember to copy and put in your users do a double click on the thing you want to copy and then you
paste it normally here you pasted and then you click on continue.
Pretty simple.
So now as you can see here we are presented with a screen that says customized denken.
So what do we do here.
I would suggest you to click on the button that says insults are just appliance.
We're going to click on this and Jenkyns.
Where you going to see these later.
Jinking has a lot of plug ins and a plug in is nothing else but like a tool an extension for something.
So Jenkyns it's quite powerful but you can still plug in in a plug in is going to give you additional
functionalities for Jenkyns.
So in this case we're going to install the suggested plug ins by Jenkyns because for sure we're going
to need it in the future.
So this is going to take a while because it needs to connect to the Internet and then download the files
and install them into Jenkyns.
I will pause the video and now will come back when it has finished great.
So did download already finished.
And now we have a screen here that tells us to create a user and as you can see here it says OK please
create the first admin user.
So we're going to call it admin.
Or you can call it whatever you want.
We're gonna give you the password.
Please give us trank password.
I will give you the one two three four one two three four.
And actually if you want to do for to everything.
OK.
So we're going to give the full name.
Let's say that this is going to be Jenkyns at man and let's say that the male of this guy is like Jenkin's
at gmail dot com just to say something.
OK.
Don't click on the save and continue.
We click on never here and here this is going to ask for a day you are all.
So for now we're just going to leave it like this.
We click save and finish and then we are done.
Finally we click on start using Jenkyns.
And here we have the screen that allows us to lug God and lock in.
So if we click on Loog out here then we put the credentials that we created ad man and one two three
four is a puzzle where we can click on Kyp mayor saying then let's click it and then let's hit design
button.
Cool.
So here we are in the Jenkin's dashboard and then we're going to start having a lot of fun with all
of these features tools and icons that you can see here.
It's a dummys.
Any video.
And see you in the next lesson.