Hello and welcome back in this video we're going to be changing gears I pay the kids we're going to
start using a DNS local DNS.
So for doing days we need to open up a notepad and we're going to click on recked click Run is that
minutes later when we are heater let's select the final occasion open.
Let's go to your Windows partition in my case it's Windows see.
So let's look for Windows.
Let's look for system 32 here.
OK let's look for drivers and drivers we click on each PC.
And after that here we just click on all the files.
When we're presented to DS We're going to choose the hosts file and what we're going to do is to graph
the IP address that you can select from puti or from your web browser and we're going to paste that
AP here.
Please don't include this HDB.
So the IP only and after that you can give a name that you on any name it's OK.
So for now we're just going to say like Jenkin's out local and we're going to save file save after that
you can close it and you can open a new tap and you can type Jenkin's that local call on ADHD hit enter
and Magique you have not created a local DNS.
So for days we can reach Jenkin's using these.
And even we can modify our poor decision in order to change their IP and start using the DNS.
So if you want to you can use instead of using the IP address here you can use the DNS that we have
just created which is Jenkin's that local.
So I'll see you in the next PDU.