Hello and welcome back.
OK guys this is a pretty quick video and I'm doing this because I've taken a look at DVD-R's and I have
seen that when we were using puti for you could be ok.
Bad in this case the video doesn't look good or it doesn't look pretty clear.
So what I'm going to do here is that I have already installed Ubuntu which is a subsystem for Windows.
If you're using Windows and you can just go ahead and install it and from now on I won't be using puti
anymore.
Instead I'll be using is H.
Jenkins.
Jenkins that low cut.
Remember that we created that DNS before he'd enter and I'll just give the puzzle one two three four.
And as you can see here DS actually works the same way that puti does.
But the thing is that here the script looks quite better and the definition is better.
Kids at UNO in Pudi.
The colors are not good for recording videos.
So probably as you can see the difference this is why it is actually stronger.
And there's one therefore I know that you're going to like to watch this instead of watching two deputy.
You can use one to install it in the Microsoft story if you want or you can keep using Pootie.
I suggest you to keep using Pootie because that's cool you are going to use it in the future or maybe
a job or whatever and it's cool that you know how to use boody.
But if you want to go ahead and use Xubuntu it's OK.
It's exactly the same thing we're doing and as a stage connection and that's what really mattered.
So in here as you can see I'm connected to the Jenkin's machine that we created which is actually using
this IP address.
And this is the virtual machine that we created before.
So this is exactly the same machine that Elvie using this because you know it's actually better for
you to see the screen for the resolution of the videos.
So when I drew on L-L you see things clearer than what you would use in Pootie.
So this is just for you to feel comfortable with the videos and I'll see you in the next lesson.