Ok cool.
So now that we have configured everything in that we're using a better interface.
We are going to start learning how to use Jenkin's remember that if you do an L as you're going to see
these folder which is jinking Zeta we created that for before.
So just go ahead and change directory to that folder and if you need LS you're going to see the doctor
compose for you are going to use these docs recomposed file a lot because remember that this file contains
the definitions for the service itself.
So if we go to the browser now and we reload we have the service up and running.
But what happens if we want to stop the service or if we want to reboot or machine then to stop the
service we need to do at Duckery compose stop.
And this is going to stop the service itself.
So if we reload here the service is no longer alive.
If we do a duck croupiers you see that there is no container running.
Therefore you have a network here.
So if you want to start your service you do at daquiri compose start and then you do a ducker appears
and you see that the container is actually up and running.
So if I were reloading here it takes some seconds for Jenkins to completely Buddh up.
So that's how you work with this.
Maybe if you want to use service you are going to deduct or compose maybe a restart Jenkin's which is
the name of the service that you want to restart.
This is going to stop it and then it's going to start to go back and what happens if you want to completely
delete your entire service.
So.
OK.
You are going to do a daquiri composed down and this down is going to delete everything related to disserve
is that it's not going to delete.
Well we say from the volumes do you remember divulgence if we take color darker compose file we see
that indecorum pad we have a volume which is this one.
And if we do analysis here we're going to see all of the files that belong to Jenkyns.
So if we recreate that this service this is going to look for the files in this folder and then is going
to map those files into that container itself.
So let's do this joker composed Abdul-Hadi creates the service or recreates the services.
So if we do that Dr. Pierce does services up and running so let's keep the browser and see what happens.
So as you can see Jenkins is just getting ready to work and we should have all the configuration that
we have already done like installing plugins or configuring the admin password and all of that stuff.
So these videos for those guys who don't know how to use Dharker or for people who have never used doctor
before and don't know how to use Dr. compote.
So that's pretty simple.
Does the doctor compose up to create a service or is recreated a stop for a stop in it start for it
start to narrow and down for delay in it.
So this is pretty cool.
Our Jenkin's services are really ready to accept connections.
So we kind of start playing around with this so see in the next lesson.