Hello and welcome back here we're going to take a look how are we going to build our love for a tree.
So as you can see here I'm using Windows and probably you are going to be using Windows.
So.
OK.
The first thing that we're going to do we're going to take this laboratory using a vertical box.
So if you have vertical bugs go ahead to Verd for bugs that work and install it for Windows.
It's pretty simple to just download it.
Click next next next and then you have virtual box installed.
So we're going to install a virtual machine a Linux machine using sento So we're going to go into centers
monumental ISO which is going to show as the ISO for center is in its minimal version.
So OK here we are a we have we're going to click on the first link and as you can see here it's going
to start downloading the image I already downloaded before.
So I'm going to go ahead and council lead and as you can see here DS is there.
Resoled.
So after we have these eyes are already downloaded.
What were we going to do that we're going to create a virtual machine based on these eyes.
So for that I'll see you in the next lesson.