Kilo and welcome back OK here we already download are image.
Please be sure that it image that you download.
It's going to be sent to seven as you can see here and there it is a 64 version as you can see here.
So OK once we have these image what we're going to do is we're going to create a virtual machine using
this image and a virtual box.
So let's go ahead and open up a little box.
We're going to click on new.
Then we're going to give it a name like Jenkin's or you can name it as you want.
We're going to say that the machine is Linux.
I think we don't have Santo's here.
We don't have.
So we're going to use Redhat as I told you it should be 64 bit.
So we're going to do.
We're going to click next.
We're going to give it for now I think two gigabytes for a ram so we're going to click next.
We're going to create a hard disk now because we don't have any hard disk.
We're going to click and create.
We're going to click on next here next and we're going to give it.
I don't know let's give it like 20 to get bytes.
OK so let's we can create an OK.
We have already our machine created.
So let's go ahead to settings.
And let's go to network ones we are here.
We need to define which adapter we are going to use so we can use as you can see here a lot of adapters
for discourse.
We're going to be using the bridge adapter so we have a Indie's rubdown as you can see here a lot of
adapter's via's And these are virtual adapters so we don't want these ones we could want these or this.
The first one which is Ethernet or the last one which is wireless depends on you.
So for example in the course of using the Ethar and connections which means that my computer is always
going to be connected to the network using a court or a wire it means that the connection is going to
be always the ethernet connection or if you know that your computer is always using Wi-Fi then you should
bind your virtual machine to wireless.
It depends on you.
Please make sure that the connection that you specify here is always active whenever you turn on your
virtual machine.
So for now as you can see here I will be choosing an ethernet connection and then clicking OK.
And then we're going to click on unstored.
So after we click on it our machine is going to boot up it's going to start and we will need to select
a startup disk.
So as you may guess we're going to use the ISO that we downloaded previously or are you going to go
into downloads and we're going to look for it centers.
This is the one that we downloaded with click on start then OK it's powering up.
As I told you before if your if you are not using Windows then you can just skip these videos and use
your Linux desktop.
But if you have Windows then you should keep with these ideas.
OK.
So what we're going to do here is that we're going to use the rules of the keyword to select installs
and those ones we're here Anner and we we.
So let's wait until something appears on the screen.
Cool as you can see here you have the welcome page and you have in these left side hand.
You have the language so we're going to use English for these keywords and here let's just click and
continue so this is cool.
Once you click on continue then we're going to have these ice cream here where we need to configure
a couple of things.
As you can see here on this software it's selection.
This is a specified as a minimal installation cool that we go into the installation.
What I click on here and we're going to use the automatically partition because it's OK just for testing.
So we're going to click on Don and then we're going to go into the network and we're going to see the
Ethernet the aperture that we created before and we're going to just turn these on as you can see it
actually retrieves an IP enth and we're gonna use this IP address in the future.
So for now we're done with this list click done.
And finally after we have configure everything that is needed we're going to hit the begin installation
button.
So we hit this and then we're going to create a password.
So for now I'm just going to say one two three four one two three four.
OK.
And we're going to click on done twice.
Now I don't know if we need to create a user let's create a user Let's say I want to create a user which
is going to call Jenkin's McHale and Jenkins and we're going to make these user.
And that means Strader because we want these user to be able of using sudo.
So we mark this and then we're going to give you the password.
We're you going to say one two three four again one two three four and then we're gonna click on Don.
So now the only one thing that we need to do is just to wait until this installation gets completed.
And after that we will have our machine ready.
So we kind of start playing around with Jenkin's that are Amazon and more.
So let's wait until these installation finishes.
I will puzzle you and I will come back once it has finished cool.
So these are already finished.
So the only one thing that is left is that not when you click this reboot button and then our machine
is going to rebuild.
So let's get it.
Let's click on Rivard and then we need to wait until the machine boots up and then we're going to be
ready to start playing around with Jenkyns.
See you in the next lesson.