Ok cool.
So now we have our mission ready and we're going to log in.
So we're going to use the user Jenkin's that we created and we're going to give the powers were 1 2
3 4 that we created.
Ok cool.
So here we are now.
What we want to know is the IP of this machine.
So we type IP a hit enter and then you're going to see the IP address right here.
This is my IP address.
So you are going to probably have an IP address like 1 9 2 1 6 8 something that something.
But don't worry you just use that IP.
So now that we have these IP addresses we want to connect to these IP using the sage but how do we do
it easy.
We go to Google and then we're going to look for puti here.
Beauty is a client for S-sh on Windows.
So we just go here we click here and then we should be using 64 bit as I told you before.
So we're going to download this.
And that's pretty simple.
We wait until the download finishes and then we're just going to go here.
Are you going to click on this.
We're going to click next.
I already have these installs so you should click on next but I'm going to click on repeller and next
next next and this is going to do all the work.
So cool once puti is installed you can see that I already create a shirt here but you can look for it
on your applications.
Or you type pretty.
And there you go.
So now what we're going to do is we're going to graph the IP address and we're going to create a connection.
So OK the first thing that we're going to do is that you are going to probably want to have the appearance
to increase the font size.
So you go here into window perience and click on change.
Now you can choose the size that you want the fun that you want.
I'm going to choose a 12 size I'm going to click OK then I'll be back to the session.
And I will type the IP address that is in here the left.
So that is 10 dot 130 thirty nine DOD 2 5 4.
Cool.
So now I will give in the safe session.
I will give you the name like Jenkin's machine or whatever you want.
And then I will click on safe.
Cool.
So now I can just closed and I can open it again.
And as you can see here here is my connection.
Then if I just want a loaded I just click on this and I click on the button.
And as you can see here it appears the IP and appearance it appears are where it conflagration.
So once we are here we click open and then we're going to log in as these are Jenkyns.
Using 1 2 3 4 cool.
So we are really logged in into this machine.
So what do we do here.
That's pretty simple.
We connected to there's a machine in here from Pootie using as a sage and why you may be asking.
And that's pretty simple.
It's because managing things from Pudi is actually pretty simple and it's even easier done doing it
from the virtual box window.
So we're going to keep this machine powered on.
So we're going to minimizers And OK we are as you can see in the same machine but now we're connected
through the which is pretty cool.
So now if you type IP A You are going to see the exact same IP address that you saw before.
So OK you already know how to connect to your machine using Pootie.
So let's do it again.
If you want to close or you just close it open up booty after you are here.
What you are going to do is that you're going to click on your Jenkin's machine state where you can
actually download then click Open logon as the user Jenkyns give it a password.
Please remember that you need it.
Your machine needs to be powered on before doing this because if it's not powered on then you're going
to have some errors.