Hello and welcome back in the previews VDU we created that connection through Pudi using S-sh to connect
to our virtual machine.
We are very connected here as you can see.
And now what we're going to do is we're going to use Duckery if you have never used it before.
Don't worry we're going to learn a little bit of daquiri here.
And you must know that doctor is only available for certain platforms on Linux.
So in this case I'm going to look for a Santo's doctor for Central because we're going to start looking
for the documentation.
Something pretty important please before doing it.
Make sure that you can reach Internet from your machine.
So if you type ping Google dot com you should have announced are like this.
OK.
So where are you going to look for dear's resort which is the first one.
And as you can see here on the left side these are the steps to install darker on the Santo's or DVN
or Fedora or Jew or whatever you have use to create a virtual machine.
And we're going to install this as you can see here we're just going to copy this command and we're
going to pay sitting here.
Oh how you pays in Pudi.
That's a good question.
You pays using the right click button on your mouse.
So you click your right button on your mouse and then you can paste it.
Cool.
So what we're going to do here is that we're going to pasted.
We hit enter and then we give the password of 1 2 3 4.
After doing this as you can see there is going to be as crane that is going to show you all that installation
for these packages.
So let's wait until this finishes.
Great.
The insulation already finished.
So where you going to be following the guide.
Where are you going to copy and paste these command which is going to as you can see here it's going
to out that repository for St. Louis.
Please remember that these steps are for St. Joe's Only if you are using in-order distribution.
Please read the Debian Fedora Ubuntu documentation.
OK so the next thing that we're going to do is that we're going to install the repository as simple
as this.
Jim in Soldat Kurt dasht CD.
That's it.
So this is going to ask for approval.
Where you gonna say yes here.
Click here.
Enter.
And then we just need to wait until this installation finishes.
It's going to ask for approval again to you.
Yes.
And then we wait until this finishes.
It may take some minutes.
Don't worry if the screen gets stuck for some seconds it's normal.
OK.
As you can see here Dean Salesian already finished and we are ready to go.
So after this we're done with this guy we can just start the service.
As you can see here we're just going to copy this command and we're going to start to dock her servies.
Now we're going to naval the darkhorse service at boot.
It means that whenever our machine reboots the car service is going to start with our system.
So for doing days we type pseudo system CTO in naval docker.
OK.
Nice.
And now if you want to test your installation you do a duck or Piers and you have a natural heater.
So how do you fix these errors.
This is pretty simple.
We're going to do a Suda user mode dodge a G and then we say Dr. Jenkins we don't enter.
And what do we do here.
User Mode is Lillenas command that allows us to modify an existing user as you can see here.
We're using the user Jenkyns.
So we are telling here to Linux this whereas say inhaling X plays at the user Jenkin's to dig group
daquiri.
So that's what we have done.
And if we tap Dr. Pierce we still have that error and that's because we need to look out and then look
back in.
So we're going to look out of here and we're going to open up our decision again.
We click on load we can open then we have the user Jenkin's that allowed to report and we try again
type in darker and nice.
This is where it can like a term.