Hello and welcome back into previews.
So doctor and now we're going to install a utility which is called Dharker compose.
So if you type croupiers you should have no reverse at this point.
And now we're going to start Dr. compose.
So where did you go to our friend Google.
And we're going to look for Dr. compose installation.
Nice.
We'll look forward to first resolved.
Click on that and then there is a part here where he has land and so we click on linens and we're just
going to copy and paste this command over and copy and we're going to paste it in here.
We give the word password 134.
After you've done this you can do a pseudo change mode flossed X which means we're going to give executable
permissions to user local does it compose.
As you can see here.
This is where we are downloading the vinery to these locations so we give it executable permissions.
So after we do it we can test it by doing a Duckery compose and then we hit enter and we should have
this out.
And that's it.
You have installed doc or compose.