Hello and welcome back in this Liz.
We're going to learn how to install Jenkyns and we're going to install Jenkin's using Duckery.
That's why we installed daquiri before.
OK.
So as you may know or if you don't know don't worry.
But Duckery uses something called an image and image is like.
And is nap sheared off a conflagration.
So in this case we're going to look for a Jenkin's image which has already all the configuration.
And we just need to run that image and then we will have our Jenkin's server up and running in some
minutes.
So let's head to Google dot com and let's look for Dr. Jenkins image.
We hit enter and then we're going to go to our first resort and as you can see here we have these Jenkin's
which is the official in March for a doctor.
So we're going to copy this command and this command is going to download the image.
So we go here and what we're going to do is we're going to pay this command and we hit enter OK.
As you can see the image is already downloading.
We only need to wait until the process completes and we are almost done.
This is the magic of Doctor doctor allows you to create services quite easy with images.
So you only need to have one image and then you're going to be able to pick up one service pretty fast
and that's cool.
You just need to create an image or look for an existing name and run that image and then you have your
servers up and running.
Don't worry if you don't know Dharker we are going to learn here.
So OK you already downloaded this image but where is this much located.
Well if you type darker images then you are going to see your image here which is pretty good.
It's a little bit heavy but don't worry.
OK so we have if you must know if you type jocker info and you grab for rude you are going to know we're
Dharker is saving the files.
So this is the location.
If you do something like sudo do dash is age and then you give the path you're going to know how much
this pays is that Kurt taken in this case they taking this size because we downloaded this image.
Ok cool.
So we already downloaded the Jenkin's image.
Now it's time to run it.
So for that.
See you in the next lesson.