Hello and welcome back.
The first thing that we're going to do is we're going to create a directory which is going to be called
Jenkyns.
You can create it whatever you want.
In this case the path is as large hum Jenkins and Jenkin's as you can see here.
I just created a directory here.
If a journalist here is the directory in befool pad for a directory is that current directory Pazz this
pad.
So let me just rename this directory because you may be confused so let's rename it.
And we're going to call that Jenkin's data for example.
So the full path for Jenkyns data is going to be less home Jenkyns and Jenkin's data perfect.
These directories empty as you can see because we haven't created anything but we're going to create
things.
OK.
We created the directory.
Now we're going to move into that directory.
We don't have anything here but we're going to create a sample daquiri compose file.
So we're Type VII docker compose that yemo.
This is important.
This name is pretty important so please keep it like this.
And vi is a text editor for Linux.
So we're going to hit enter.
And then we're going to start typing.
Did Doc compose fire before doing a duck recomposed file is they can the script is a definition.
So here we're going to define which services we want to spin.
So in this case for now we want to spin a Jenkin's server.
So we're going to start with this file.
So we say Version 3 that's the current version of Duguid composed don't worry.
And now we say it services.
So in services we're going to define our Jenkin's server and this denken server will have some properties
so we can define the container name container name and where are you going to call it Jenkyns simple.
Now we're going to define the image.
So is a image and then the name that is going to go here.
Is the name that we downloaded in the preview video.
So we type darker image.
And here we have the name.
So we're going to copy this name.
Are going to open up again or Dr. composed file.
And we're going to pay these in here.
Cool.
Oh a pretty quick tap.
If you don't know how to exit of this crane this is pretty simple.
You hit escape then you head shift and the colon key then you press w in Q Which means right and quit.
So we hit enter and you are really quite cool.
So OK we're ready to find a container name and image Waddle's zoo in it.
I'm going to leave you does Tim played here and this Tom played.
You can actually just copy and paste it if you run right.
Use it or you can manually type.
There is no problem.
So we're going to find the poor it's what our good port.
So we're going to say port and we define an A right of port that we're going to say that we want to
expose the port of Jenkin's using the port 80 on our machine and we're going to map that port internally
to the container on port 80.
Don't worry we will take a look on this later.
What else do we need.
We need to Baalim what is a Baalim.
OK.
You must know that in Dharker when you create a container when you use Pin-Up your service all the data
which is within the container is going to be destroyed if you don't save that data into a volume.
So we say volumes here in this case and we're going to say OK we want to create a folder which is going
to be called Jenkin's folders.
So let's use the coring part for now.
Are you going to say PWT which means PWT a career path.
And we're going to create a folder which is going to be called Jenkin's home for example.
And we are going to map these for other.
OK.
First we need to create this folder in our machines already in a copy of this
and are you going to go out of Bam and we're going to create a directory here.
So we click make your home make sure you don't put the lash make Jenkin's hum.
Hit enter.
Any of you do.
Unless you should see Jenkin's home folder at the same level of the daquiri compose file.
So OK the full pop Ferdie's is the PWB which can be represented with this variable.
You do an EC2 loops.
So this is the correct path plus your four letter to folder that you have just created and this is the
full path as you can see.
OK so where are you going to get back to work Dharker compose file.
And we are already defined as this is the host Baalim.
Now we're going to map it to a container.
So how do we do this within the container.
The darker image eases these folder to his tour of the file.
So where are you going to copy the location where you put a calling here.
And then we paste the location.
So we're saying OK Doctor please whatever you are right here which is going to be all of the files for
Jenkyns.
Please save those files in the directory that I have just created.
Cool.
And now we need to define a network.
So we say we one this to be in the network that we haven't created the network net.
So let's go here in the same text file at the same level of services where are going to create a section
which is going to be called networks networks.
We put a call on an underneath of these.
We're going to create a net network.
So OK we're saying Please Doctor create a network using these instruction which is going to be called
net and then we're going to use that here.
And where are you going to include the Jenkin's server or the Jenkyns service within the network.
So that's pretty cool.
I think this is everything we need.
We're going to save the file and we are done.
So let's recap what we just did.
And if we do that cat in the duck recomposed GMO file We're going to see that we're using a version
3 of Dr. compose.
We have defined a service.
Its name is Jenkins they contain our name is going to be Jenkin's the image that it's going to use as
the Jenkin's slash Jenkins image.
It's going to export the port 80 80.
It's going to save all the information in these folders that we created.
And this is going to bind the service into an Network which is called Net Envy's network is being created
here.